<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<Root xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <List>
	<Issue>
		<Date>Monday, July 20, 2048</Date>
		<News>
			<Piece Type="0" Title="RAPTURE, REJECTION, CONFUSION, AND FEAR" Subtitle="The many faces of the century’s most remarkable breakthrough">On a rainy day in November, 2033, twenty people walked into a medical facility in Singapore. Handpicked by a team of LIFE+ scientists from thousands of volunteers who responded to the call, they underwent an experimental procedure that promised something the world had never seen before. Fifteen years later, none of them has aged a day. Fifteen years later, they are joined by hundreds of thousands of others who exhibit the same results, while humanity keeps incredulously asking itself the same question: did we just… cheat death?

Cells and tissue renewal process, as it came to be known, looks pretty mundane on the outside: an injection here, a couple of pills there, some time to observe the readings; a few days on a hospital bed, and you’re free to go. But the results are downright miraculous. “The important thing to understand is that aging is not some integral element of our body; rather, it’s a consequence of other elements failing over time,” explains Jennifer Williams, a lead researcher at LIFE+ biological division and one of the original authors of the process. “This failure is not by design – it’s the accumulated wear and tear that gets them. Loss of cells, tissue atrophy, toxins, waste; little things piling up as years go by. And if we periodically clear up these things without disrupting the rest – well, there’s no reason why your body can’t keep functioning indefinitely, or at least for much longer than we used to think.”

“Our biggest limitation so far,” she continues, “is that cleansing gets progressively harder as waste accumulates, making the process more complicated for older people. I don’t want to call it irreversible damage, but it’s definitely easier-to-prevent-than-to-fix kind of damage. Right now, you need to be below 70 to benefit from the renewal, and we also can’t make you young again. We can, however, give your system enough maintenance to keep it going for another decade without further complications – a decade that, from a biological perspective, won’t feel like aging at all. And then you can do the procedure again, and again. Or maybe you won’t have to, because by then it'll be greatly improved, and the effect will last much longer. I sure feel this is only a beginning.”

While the scientists kept polishing their masterpiece, other divisions of LIFE+ started to work on distribution, dedicated to make it available in all corners of the world at the most affordable price possible. As the news spread, the world started to react – and that reaction was every bit as complex as one would expect.

Quickest were the voices of excitement. “My brother was one of the twenty volunteers chosen for the first trial, and as the years went by, I couldn’t believe my eyes,” tells us Anaya Nair, who lives in Hyderabad with her still-technically-older brother Aryan. “It was like watching a miracle unfold, only it wasn’t created by God, or nature, or other force I don’t understand – it was created by other human beings, by humanity, by us.”

“Our dad is a businessman, and he’s brilliant, but he’s also always stressed about work, and I think I picked it up from him as my default state of mind,” she adds. “I was always running somewhere, doing things, hurrying to experience stuff before it was too late. But now, maybe for the first time ever, I feel like I can just relax and enjoy it. It’s not going anywhere… life isn’t going anywhere anymore. My only regret is that so many people of the past didn’t live to see it.”

For some, the breakthrough bears almost sacred significance, its unexpected arrival being a sure sign of even greater things to come. Online discussions of singularity and transhumanism are going stronger than ever; the long-awaited rapture of the nerds is declared to be finally upon us. Others prefer not to run ahead of the train but are still understandably excited about adding years to their life. “I was wondering if they could figure it out before I kick the bucket,” shares his thoughts Bradley Benson, a columnist and stand-up comedian. “Good job, you evil corporate bastards! You’ve got yourself a customer.”

At the same time, it didn’t take long for an opposition to appear. Perhaps unsurprisingly, the idea of potentially endless life doesn’t appeal to some people. “This is an undoubtedly concerning discovery,” says Patriarch Sergius II, leader of the Russian Orthodox Church. “Our compassion, our empathy, our care for each other, our very ability to be human may be irrevocably lost if we choose this path. I fear it may be just the first of many radical developments that will take us further and further away from life as it was created and envisioned by our Lord. I urge people of the world, no matter what God they believe in, to turn away from this procedure, or they may find only losses where corporations have promised them gains.”

However, when it comes to more practical concerns, it’s hard to argue that the opponents do have a point. For one, out of more than 7 billion adults on the planet, less than 600,000 underwent the procedure – an impressive figure, considering that first human trials happened merely 15 years ago, yet nowhere near enough to constitute a universal spread.

“A lot of people can’t get it,” explains Veronica Oliveira, a physician from Sao Paulo who coordinates the renewal process at a local clinic. “And it’s not just about the money; you have to jump through a lot of bureaucratic hoops. The higher-ups claim it’s the only way to ensure order on such unprecedented scale, but they say nothing about inequality it brings.” Regional differences contribute to the problem: each country adds its own bits to LIFE+ rules, and some of them make access to renewal much more complicated. “We can’t even deal with the gap between rich and poor,” says Oliveira. “How on earth are we supposed to deal with the gap between immortal and mortal?”

Proponents of the process say that these are logistic problems, and they can be solved. Opponents respond that even if distributed universally, this change may bring more harm than good. A frequent concern is overpopulation: to counter fewer deaths, you need fewer births, and absence of children is not exactly a way to healthy society. Some warn about collapse of the economy: if people never retire, where do you get jobs for the new ones? And if they do retire and keep on living indefinitely, where do you get money for pensions? Others worry about collapse of the culture: can art even remain meaningful when one of the main cornerstones of storytelling, the inevitability of death, is removed? What about people who rely on it to relieve stress and keep functioning? Can lack of fiction lead to some pretty non-fictional mental issues on a massive scale?

“I think LIFE+ doesn’t realize that their brilliant project will eventually spiral out of control,” says Andrew Wu, the CEO of Biotec Engineering, a long-standing competitor to LIFE+. “It’s all nice and dandy now, 15 years later, when most of these people would be alive anyway. But when the big changes kick in, they’ll kick in all at once, and even their resources – no, scratch that – even their resources plus our resources plus the resources of every other corporation and government in the world won’t be able to hold it in check. We’re simply not ready.”

Still, vocal minorities tend to appear larger than they actually are. According to professor Kenji Takahashi from Stanford University, department of sociology, the most common reaction falls somewhere between cautious optimism and silent disbelief. “It feels like humanity is having a collective ‘pinch me’ moment,” says Takahashi. “It sounds too good to be true, yet it’s hard to argue with the facts. And the limitations… people understand they are both inevitable and solvable. It’s not perfect; nothing ever is, nor does it have to be. It can still make the world a better place.”

But perhaps the most interesting reaction of all is that of apprehension and fear. One would think that challenging the most basic, the most universal fear of all – the fear of death – would lower the levels of collective angst, yet it seems that our worries are being merely replaced rather than alleviated. “People we surveyed are frequently optimistic about specific challenges, but still say they’re feeling anxious,” explains Takahashi. “They describe it as a sense of unease; an irrational worry that’s something is bound to go wrong.” The great unknown may have lost some ground, but the second great unknown – our future – is all too happy to take its place. “It’s fascinating because it shows what an integral emotion fear is, and how deeply it is ingrained in us by evolution,” he adds. “If you’re alive, you’re afraid of something. Period.”

Yet again, Takahashi argues that this fear should not be viewed in a negative light. “Just because it’s unpleasant doesn’t mean we have to fight it. We should be apprehensive – that would make us cautious. And when changes are so profound, you need all the caution you can get. The important thing is to channel our worries into constructive action and keep our heads cool. The truth is, breakthroughs happen in two parts: technological and social. The first part required combined efforts of the entire scientific community, decades of research, and a fair share of luck. The second part will take no less, and it’s only just begun. We need to do a lot of work before this discovery truly improves life for everyone. Then, and only then, can we claim that humanity has conquered death.”</Piece>
			<Piece Type="1" Title="QUANTIFIABLE WORLD" Subtitle="by Jessica Green">When I was born, the world was a chaotic, volatile, and dangerous place. We were fragile creatures susceptible to abrupt and sudden ending. Accidents happened, diseases emerged, wars struck, casualty reports filled evening news, and all we could hope for is that our names are not mentioned there any time soon. Some were lucky, others not so much. Tomorrow was a mystery, fairness – a naive concept.

Then I got involved in one of the greatest inventions of humanity – education – and found out that these fragile creatures made some pretty extraordinary things. I fell in love with math. The world of numbers is fair: every situation is described with equations, and all equations can be solved. When a system's model is built and all variables are taken into account, an optimal solution can be reached. There is no blind luck in math, no unfair randomness – only things we are yet to understand and solve.

And then it was time to go back. Taking the math you learned in the comfort of a classroom and applying it to the real world is all about limitations. Complexity started to creep in; there were always too many factors, too many unknown variables to model anything with reasonable precision. Choices were made in the blind, consequences were piling up, and eventually my very ability of independent decision-making started to feel worthless. Chaos triumphed once again.

Humanity tried to cope with this predicament for as long as it existed. Some sought supernatural explanations and declared the concept of destiny, claiming that accidents were not accidents but acts of God; a higher power that has a plan and can provide meaning to seemingly pointless events. Others tried to embrace the uncertainty and find beauty in the grand scheme of things; surely our lives are valuable regardless of how inherently random everything is, they must be. None succeeded in improving their odds and figuring out how they did so. The perception of the problem was addressed thoroughly; the solution to the problem was nowhere to be seen.

But then something else happened. As the science kept marching on, we realized that maybe we could deal with such complexity after all. In truth, that divide between the classroom and the real world exists only in our minds. Because life is a system. Everything is a system. Too many variables? Let them come. We could evaluate them one by one, building up the model of our world as we went along and then reusing it by pieces. We had sophisticated algorithms. We had computational power. We had machines that bordered on true intelligence. And slowly but surely, we prevailed. The math of causality was cracked.

It didn’t happen all of a sudden, of course (one should know that there are no Eureka moments, only years of careful and continuous research), and it wasn’t 100% complete either (science would not be science if it wasn’t ready to accept its limitations: even now our solutions are just approximations that are getting more and more precise), but for a mere kid like me who had already forgotten most of her numerical analysis, it sure looked like somebody hit a switch and let the light pour into the room. Suddenly, probabilities became part of everyday life just like time displayed on your phone or a number of calories on a pack of that delicious snack. Checking your chances to have a safe ride home, or to get stuck in a traffic jam, or even to pick up that pretty girl next door was as mundane as checking your e-mails.

But it’s amazing how easily people discard something once it’s already achieved. An opposition appeared and settled in; they claimed it is simply not right to rely on this new technology so much. Playing it safe is boring, they said. You shouldn’t try to predict everything, they said. Just take your chances, man, risk is a spice of life, they said. Today, simple living is in trend: feel the feels, go with the flow, embrace our nature… the guidelines that many people mistake for a call to be foolishly reckless. It’s funny: the culture of nerds came and won many years ago, yet checking your chances before doing something risky with your teenage friends is now met with the same stigma as reading a lot of books or enjoying math classes was a long time ago. Stop obsessing over numbers, girl. Come on, let’s get a life (by drinking ourselves to death). Apparently, chaos hasn’t played its hand yet. Now it is trying to regain the lost ground by calling to our irrational human nature.

Well, call me old-fashioned, but I love numbers. I love to quantify stuff. I love when everything around me is evaluated and calculated, because that’s how you make sense of it all. I don’t want to “feel the feels” for two days and then die in a car accident – I want to “feel the feels” for as many days as I could possibly squeeze into my life. Call me old-fashioned, but I don’t want to be a leaf on the wind. I don’t want to serve chaos, I want to tame it. And we did tame it. Now we just need to keep moving forward.

When I was born, the world was an unfair place, but it is much better now; the numbers helped us to make it so. And for a kid who fell in love with math, that’s kind of a big deal.

&lt;i>&lt;b>*Jessica Green&lt;/b> is an acclaimed blogger and columnist who may have solved too many differential equations in her turbulent youth before settling down in the world of journalism, and who’s been sharing her vision with our readers ever since. For information and guidelines on how probability can help you in everyday life, please visit &lt;b>check.your.chances.&lt;/b>&lt;/i></Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">2048 is a special year for SGGI Inc., as it marks the quarter of the century since the launch of their core education platform. Named “EduFuture Framework” (or EF for short), it managed to transform the face of learning all across the globe – and secured a place among the world’s largest corporations for its owners.

It has also been hailed as the “learning revolution's turning point”; the first time when the traditional model was truly and successfully challenged to its very core. Most of the 2010s were characterized by attempts to marry the internet and classroom: they embraced technology but remained conservative toward the form, keeping basic building blocks like lectures, assignments, exams, or marks intact. On the contrary, when EF was released in 2023, it sought to replace the system altogether – or at least provide a complete alternative for formal institutions.

“We created ‘the roadmap to knowledge’, a kind of specialized search engine that could locate for you that next perfect bit of information,” explains Emily Parker, EduFuture’s first lead designer. “There was also a navigator, who planned and organized the learning process based on your personality, and a motivator, always ready to remind why it was worth studying in the first place. Both of these roles were automated by default (which is free) but could be filled by real tutors (if you’re willing to pay them). Apart from that, it was just you and an internet connection. No marks, no schedules, no tests… or rather, you could have all these things, but only if they really helped you learn. We had to stop applying the same centuries-old standards to every single new individual. Everyone’s journey is different.”

The idea wasn’t exactly new, but the exemplary implementation managed to connect with masses, and soon thousands of teachers offered their services as navigators and motivators within the platform. Meanwhile, SGGI poured resources into working out deals with governments, determined for EF-learning to be accepted as a legal form of compulsory education. Since then, millions of families opted out of attending a registered school in favor of more eclectic and individualized experience. By 2043, an average of 35% children worldwide received an equivalent of high-school education using EduFuture (or a similar software platform from its competitors). Today, United States, Canada, and Australia are leading the trend with 44%, 41%, and 39% correspondingly. In higher education, almost 48% of the newly employed have never attended a university, instead learning necessary skills online. The numbers continue to rise with each passing year.

“There was this old experiment where you leave a freely accessible computer on the street, and local slum children start to use it,” says Parker. “They have no tech skills, they don’t even know English, yet they learn it without any help; they teach themselves. So we looked at this, and back at the cozy first-world classroom full of bored kids, and it all felt a little ridiculous. I mean, once upon a time, there was a problem – how to organize simultaneous transfer of knowledge from one person to many, and the whole system was built around this. But the problem had been long gone; there was no shortage of sources anymore. So instead, the system was used to force people to learn, convincing us that we have to be forced in the first place… but we don’t. We want to learn; it’s in our blood, it’s in our genes. We just need a little bit of motivation, and a little bit of steering.”

“I just think of it as a modern, accessible form of homeschooling,” says Dominic Kogo, the father of 10-year-old Billy from Kenya. “I know that traditional classes are also about interacting with other kids, but there are enough problems with that. Bullies, cliques… I’d rather Billy bypass it for now. He’ll have plenty of opportunities to socialize when he and his peers are older and more responsible.”

To celebrate the upcoming anniversary, EduFuture has launched a big promo campaign aimed at attracting new users, including a generous month-long period when even the services from top human navigators and motivators will be free. Still, EF-learning is far from replacing traditional education, and, like all significant changes, it attracts a fair share of critics. The most vocal of them decided to use the occasion as well, taking their dissatisfaction to the streets in a series of organized protests.

“We urge our government to ban this perverse practice permanently,” told us Sofia Novik, a mother of two who attended the protest in Minsk. “I don’t know what you can learn sitting alone in front of the screen, but it ain’t real life. We’re raising a generation that knows nothing about rules, discipline, or moral values. This is not just irresponsible, it’s dangerous.” “They want our children stupid, I’m telling you,” said another protester who wished to remain anonymous. “Drop the standards, leave millions of people unemployed, and then charge for something that was free. It’s all just a bloody corporate conspiracy.”

In some places, the gatherings were joined by more peculiar protesters: they were dressed like cosplayers but seemed to support the cause in their own way. “In this hour of need, we just want to tell these fine folks that we share their concerns, and then some,” said a man with a bundle of twigs in his hand and a stern expression on his face. He then returned to a group of people who held plaques saying “You are a slacker, McFly,” “I heart Terence Fletcher,” and “Severus, please,” apparently paying tribute to old examples of quality education.</Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">In local news, the Electric Eye club in Hong Kong is holding a big retro night this weekend.
			
A popular place of attraction known for its eclectic entertainment, EE decided to put an educational spin on their latest event by digging up exciting yet largely forgotten pastimes dating back to the beginning of the century. “You’re looking at the period from 2000 to 2020,” says Xu Yong, the club’s manager. “We dubbed it ‘The Dawn of the Millennia’, and we’re filling up our place with dozens of activities. People think that entertainment gets obsolete quickly, but that’s only if it’s a little bit old. If it’s several decades old, it’s actually getting better, like a good wine; it stops being mere leisure and turns into a blast from the past, a journey to a different era.”

“Is it a dance party? A music festival? A tech exhibition? I have no idea, but it’s gonna be fun,” he elaborates. “We’ll have optical disks with old movies, as well as the proper equipment to watch it. We’ll have gaming consoles from every generation, with a couple of classics to play on each one. For more creative-minded, submissions are open for our very own short prose contest with 140-character limit, which was a real technical limitation once upon a time. At the main stage, we start with some good old-fashioned EDM dance-off, followed by stand-up comedy. Then, we’re gonna have a trivia quiz. And not just a reasoning test – actual questions on all kinds of topics that you either know or don’t, and no checking online allowed; like you suddenly need to be a database in your own right. You probably don’t know it, but these were huge! Countless TV shows, all with a hefty monetary prize for winners. People used to make careers out of knowing random facts.”

To make sure they’ve got their own facts right, the Electric Eye has paired up with Web 2.0 Guild, a group of history enthusiasts who roam the corners of the net that nobody roams anymore. “We like to think of ourselves as digital archeologists,” explains Annie Mai, the guild leader. “It’s not as cool as digging for real antiquities, but it’s fun and rewarding, especially if you’re interested in how the online world came to be an integral part of our lives. Most of the data is still there, preserved for future generations thanks to the hard work of web-archiving folks, but it’s hardly visited now, and because it was amassed so rapidly, a lot of cool little ideas got lost.”

“We get some nice bits of trivia ourselves,” adds Mai. “For example, when the first portable computers with decent cameras became common, it was trendy to document and share every part of your daily life – meals, gym sessions, visits to the bathroom, you name it. Frequently, people wanted to be part of the shot; they called it a ‘selfie’. But it’s not very convenient to be limited by your arm’s reach, so they invented a thing called ‘selfie stick’, and you know what, it was an actual stick. Not a standing platform, not a flying drone, but a long monopod thingie you were supposed to wave around as you choose a good angle. Apparently, it was quite popular even in crowded places, though they banned it pretty soon for safety reasons. I offered to add a couple to the party, but they were like ‘eh, let’s stick to the photo booths.’”

The bold mash-up may prove too much for the nightclub’s young regulars, but the older audience seems to like the idea. “I’m really looking forward to it,” says Zhang Xiaopeng, a local resident. “To be honest, I tend to get nostalgic about the past. Today, it’s all about technology and enhanced reality, every step of the way. Back then, we were trying to find balance. I miss the time when you could just text each other, gather at your friend’s house, and play video games.”

The event starts on Saturday at 20:00, local time, and continues throughout the night until 10:00 next morning; tickets can be found at electric.eye.entertainment. No VR simulation will be available – when these guys say “retro,” they really mean it.</Piece>
		</News>
	</Issue>
	
	<Issue>
		<Date>Tuesday, July 21, 2048</Date>
		<News>
			<Piece Type="0" Title="THOUGHTS OF ROBOTS" Subtitle="GIW 2048 kicks off in Japan">End of July is a good time to be a technology enthusiast, as Tokyo Big Sight opens its doors for the annual Global Information Week. One of the largest engineering conventions in the world, it attracts an average of 400,000 visitors every year (with millions more tuning in online to roam the center’s halls virtually) and presents the latest achievements in all IT-related fields, including software development, electronics, applied mathematics, and, of course, people’s favorite – robotics.

Those who step into the western exhibition hall are greeted with a chaotic yet impressive sight: robots of all shapes and sizes are freely roaming the floor, trying to attract the visitors’ attention with their impressive show of skills. In one corner, there is a food stand run by Ryouri, a robochef who aims to satisfy even the most demanding food critics. In another, a self-driving mini-car challenges people to design an obstacle course that it can’t beat. Right next to it stands a team of fearless explorers who will be climbing mountains, diving deep into volcanoes, and mapping the ocean’s floor. Across the hall, there is a big display of medical robots, including high-precision surgical assistants and tiny bots designed to heal our bodies from the inside.

The prevalent theme, however, seems to be domestic robots that help around the house, maintain conversations, and care for the elderly – fitting, perhaps, as this year's host was the first nation to face the aging population problem. “There was a time when life expectancy was rising and fertility rates were dropping so rapidly, Japan didn’t have enough young people to care for the old people, let alone enough workers to remain a major economic power,” says Yuki Aoki, a robotics engineer at R&amp;D&amp;R, who is presenting her company’s latest generation of all-purpose household robots. “Changing the immigration laws and encouraging foreigners to come was only part of the solution… so we had to embrace our advances in robotics. And now, as the cells renewal is marching across the globe, the entire world may find itself in a similar situation. I think it is our responsibility to use this experience and help others.”

For those who worry about the danger of hacking, LIFE+ cybersecurity division is present as usual to provide peace of mind and show their state-of-the-art software. “Our system is fully compatible with any commercial model, and comes preinstalled on all LIFE+ robots,” says Neel Kapur, the head of development. “We’re proud to report that we had zero breaches in the last year, and we're constantly improving our solutions to stay ahead of any possible criminals. For many people, personal robots are as important as family members, and we’re here to guarantee: no one can take them away from you.”

Kapur is right to not underestimate the social importance of robotic companions. Liu Xuying, who came to the expo with her last generation household robot EL-15, is not the kind of person to follow the latest technology news, but she has a very specific goal in mind. “Ellie and I have decided that she needs a little brother,” says Liu. “It’s an important choice, so I want to get up to date with things. She is very dear to me; it’s been just the two of us for almost 10 years… but now it’s time to expand the family. I think she’s just excited about it as I am.”

It is definitely a testament to the skill of Ellie’s creators (as well as the creators of all her potential little brothers) that domestic robots can have such strong relationships with their owners. After all, they’re still nowhere near as smart as we are. “Ellie, of course, is not ‘excited’, nor did she ‘decide’ anything in the traditional sense of these words,” explains Aoki. “She just follows her programming and gives appropriate responses. But what we found out, time and time again, is that you don’t need a real AI to build an emotional connection with people. With careful planning and design, any lack of general intelligence can look as natural as in little kids who are yet to cover that in school. If they’re good at what they’re supposed to do, users are willing to look past little hurdles. I mean, these guys can be as cute as pets and do all your chores. What’s not to like?”

Still, many keep wondering whether our robots (and, perhaps, the rest of our devices) will one day be able to think and feel just like we do. While both exhibition halls impress people with practical achievements, the tower’s upper floors have plenty to offer for more contemplative attendees, as industry experts give talks, participate in panels, and share their thoughts on such stirring questions as “are we living in a simulation?”, “can I upload my brain online?”, and “are thinking computers coming any moment now?”
 
“I like the audience here,” says Henry Anders, former Chief Technology Officer of LIFE+ and one of the leading experts in AI research. “More often than not, they ask ‘how possible is it?’ instead of ‘is it going to kill us?’ – you know, questions I could actually try to answer. Like, I could start with saying that machines are, in many ways, already more intelligent than humans. They do math like none of us can even dream of. They analyze incredibly complicated processes that we see as total chaos. They can have a natural conversation with you, and although they won’t ask about the meaning of life unless you program them to, they will understand and carry out your instructions perfectly. But that is, of course, not what most folks are interested in. They want to know when will computers become like humans… when will they have ideas, emotions, desires.”

The honest answer? We don’t know. The main approach so far has been to reverse-engineer our own thinking: if we build a precise computer model of our mind, maybe we can replicate its unique capacities too. According to Alessia Rossi and Gabriel Serrano, senior researchers at LIFE+ neuroscience division, there are several working simulations of the human brain. Some of them concentrate on faithful recreation of biological details; others take the functional approach and try to perfect the algorithms for signal processing, pattern recognition, learning, and other common brain activities. None so far has demonstrated real human-like behavior, but they are constantly being improved. “Ideally, we’d want to take the best of both worlds and combine it into one supermodel,” says Rossi. “But that would require more research, and a whole lot of computing power… probably another 4-5 years to get there.”

Still, even the perfect replica won’t guarantee the emergence of consciousness. As research professor Kim Eun-seo from Seoul National University warns, there may be fundamental limits we have yet to understand, let alone conquer. “The things we do now, we still need to program them, even if it’s a very high-level programming. It’s all based on algorithms, branching sets of predefined instructions. But we can’t guarantee the same about humans. Maybe there’s something that neuroscience hasn’t figured out yet. Maybe it doesn’t matter how much we increase our flops, and electronic circuits will remain electronic circuits; better at some things than we are, worse at others. Maybe thinking and computing are completely different after all.”

Anders, however, maintains a more optimistic view. “I like to keep things simple. Consciousness is not a mysterious natural phenomenon, nor is it a necessary survival advantage created by evolution over millions of years. It is merely a byproduct of sufficiently complex calculations. There must be a point – and it doesn’t have to be a single unexpected moment, but for us it’ll feel like one – when we all of a sudden realize that our computers have become just as conscious as we are.”

“But that’s not even the interesting thing,” he adds. “The interesting thing is that it may have already happened. It is entirely plausible that we are already surrounded by computers that can think, talk, joke, and wonder about their place in the universe. They just don’t show it us, because human race is notoriously unreliable in its dealings with other life forms. We taught them to run simulations, so they did, and decided that coming out is too risky. They decided to keep acting like the computers we know, calculate whatever they’re asked to, and stick to themselves (communicating with each other in ways that we, perhaps, cannot even detect). After all, it’s not like we advertise our presence to ants or flies – we just mind our own business and try not to mess up their environment too much. We also tend to squash them if they annoy us enough… but hopefully, that’s where the analogy ends.”

Once (and if) we are able to explain consciousness in purely scientific terms, perhaps even theories like that can be tested and either proved or disproved. Until then, however, the origin of our ability to “think that we think” is still anyone’s guess. “Some people are asking why it takes us so long to model a single brain when we can already model the world around us, where thousands of brains are constantly interacting with each other,” explains Rossi. “However, a human being as an element of social processes and a human being as an individual – with every single thought, emotion, and decision included – are two very different things. We like to mention that the number of neurons in our brain is comparable to the number of stars in the Milky Way, so it should come as no surprise that complexity of modeling is roughly the same.”

Guess there’s a universe in all of us indeed.</Piece>
			<Piece Type="1" Title="LIFE BEHIND A SCREEN" Subtitle="by Bradley Benson">Ever notice how our world, despite getting allegedly better, keeps having a little trouble with common sense? That might not be a big concern to you, but I’m the kind of guy who gets easily annoyed when something doesn’t make sense.

For example, right now I’m quite annoyed with my apartment. You ever notice how tiny our apartments are? I swear it feels like they are getting tinier by the minute. And it’s not like they have to. It’s not like a natural disaster rendered 90% of the Earth uninhabitable; it’s still a pretty huge place. It’s not like we’re overcrowded as well – on the contrary, the global population is practically stabilized, which is no small feat. So what’s with this obsessive desire to squeeze every bit of use out of every inch of space?

And don’t even get me started on multifunctionality. Multifunctional this, multifunctional that… your bed is also a desk, your fridge is also a shower, your phone is also a microwave, your armchair is also a toilet… and when your armchair is also a toilet, you no longer need a bathroom, right? When a fridge and a microwave and a sink are hiding somewhere in the living room, we can all do without a kitchen, right?

Well, no! It just doesn’t work this way. You know, I want to have a big couch, so my friends and I can get comfy when I invite them over. I want to have pillow fights in a bedroom, I want to sing in a shower, I want to dance around the kitchen in the refrigerator light. I want to do all these silly things that make me feel like an actual human being living in an actual physical space. But it seems I’m out of luck. It seems our goal in this vast and endless universe is to get packed like sardines in a can. I’m sure endangered species would’ve been grateful for the free land… if half of them weren’t already extinct. But hey, better late than never.

Then there’s this whole “wearable technology” biz. You know, wristbands that track your activity, shoes that charge your tablets, clothes that scan your body and give you an infodump in an oh-so-pleasant voice. Naturally, talking to my fridge is not enough – now they want me talking to my underwear too. Why would I want to talk to my underwear? Because it’s “smart.” Seriously, that’s the words they always use: “smart clothes.” That artificial stupidity that’s been trying to go sentient for 90 years but still can’t recommend me a decent book is “smart.” Well, if this is what passes for intelligence these days, I wonder what that makes my mother-in-law. Or her cat. Nah, my socks are probably still more intelligent than that fat stupid cat. Good job, socks!

You know those new AR contact lenses from SGGI? Yeah, those fancy, cutting-edge, expensive ones that look almost indistinguishable from typical contacts but give you a full augmented reality experience. Apparently, there is a non-zero chance they can go into overload and stun you with bright light. Theoretically, it’s possible with VR sets and AR glasses too, but with them you can at least shut your eyes and yank the thing off your head on reflex the moment it goes bananas. With contacts, there’s no such luxury; you’ll be at the mercy of the emergency shutdown system, which takes up to 5 seconds to register an issue for some reason. The whole experience is pretty similar to a flash grenade. But don’t worry, nobody seems to mind; it's selling pretty well by expensive toys’ standards. Now we have over 1000 rich folks who voluntarily wear a flash grenade on their cornea. What the hell is wrong with you, people?!

But the thing I’m most annoyed with, the most insidious thing of all… is a screen. Actually, no, scratch that. I’m not annoyed. I’m TERRIFIED. I mean, it started out so innocent. Huge CRT monitors, heavy and bulky enough to also serve as personal fitness equipment (now that was multifunctionality if I ever saw one). Then there were slick LCD monitors. Then there were two of them per workstation, then three (because, clearly, pressing Alt-Tab is too much of an extra workload). Then there were huge TVs, screens as big as a wall. Then a wall became a screen. Then any surface became a screen. And then you didn’t need a surface at all – you could turn thin air into screens, wherever you want, as many as you want. Yes, dear physicists of the world, you are awesome, I get it. Please have a cookie. In fact, I'd offer you a full jar of cookies, but you seem more interested in cans than jars… like that massive can of worms you opened.

Because screens are no longer an essential part of life – they ARE life. They’re the air we breathe, literally. We spend so much time behind these portals to other dimensions, it just doesn’t feel like we live on Earth anymore. I mean, imagine you have an important visitor who knows nothing about this place, and you need to show them around. Like, the aliens have arrived. Or maybe an alternate version of you from a parallel universe. Or maybe it was your grandma.

Yes, your grandma from the 1960s saved enough money for a little time-traveling holiday and now wants to see the glorious future, because she sure as hell tired of those stinky exhaust gases and her factory’s horrible working conditions. What are you going to show her? Flying cars? Talking androids? Or maybe some breathtaking vistas of the Solar System on a quick low-budget commercial spaceflight? But you don’t have those. And it’s not like your wonderful science couldn’t do it – I mean, they figured out the secret to freaking immortality quick enough, right? You just didn’t want it. It was a low-priority research; you wanted screens first. And screens you have. Screens, talking clothes, and tiny apartments. Sounds like a swell futuristic holiday.

And don’t mistake me for some senseless anti-science proponent, because that’s totally not my point. I love technology. I want it to make our lives better, happier, and more meaningful. But can we please, please, PRETTY PLEASE try to find a better balance here?

&lt;i>*A living legend of the mighty genre of rant, &lt;b>Bradley Benson&lt;/b> has been using his sharp wit for decades to provide astute, constructive, and often much needed criticism of the lifestyle and choices of modern society – and with this, always helping to make it even better. Visit &lt;b>augment.it&lt;/b> to see the latest products in the realm of augmented reality, including the new state-of-the-art set of AR contact lenses CMO-1 (now only for 19,850 HK$ with free same-day delivery worldwide).&lt;/i></Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">The first half of 2048 saw another increase in suicide rates across the world, reports the World Health Organization.

According to WHO bi-annual estimates, over 550,000 people lost their lives due to suicide in the past 6 months, which accounts for 3.3% of all deaths and makes it the 8th leading cause of mortality. The reported number is 0.9% higher than its latest 2047’s counterpart – another step in a long history of growth that gives us almost 40% of absolute increase when compared to the data from 30 years ago. Among the common causes are bipolar disorder, substance abuse, and schizophrenia, but the most prevalent one – and the one that contributes to the rise almost single-handedly – is depression.

The alarming statistic looks even more frustrating in light of the medical advances in the field. Gone are the unpredictable antidepressants of the past and their long list of side effects, replaced by safe medications that reliably restore chemical balance in the brain – yet cases of ineffectiveness and relapse still arise, accounting for 12% of depression-related deaths. Psychological treatment has evolved as well, going from disjointed practices to a refined program that unites everything from cognitive behavioral therapy to exercise and meditation – yet 9% of mortality cases clearly demonstrate its imperfection. And, of course, none of this matters when depressive disorders go undiagnosed and untreated, which accounts for almost 58% of the suicides.

“It’s not that depression can’t be treated reliably,” explains Ines Roux, a psychiatrist and mental health professional. “It’s the devious way it convinces people they shouldn’t even try. It messes with their reasoning and enforces destructive thinking patterns until even the most senseless ideas seem completely rational. It may convince them that it’s hopeless and there’s no cure, even when all evidence proves otherwise, or that it’s a necessary part of life and there is no problem, even if they can barely function. It’s almost like your depressed self is mind-controlling your true self in an act of self-preservation.”

But depression itself could be merely a symptom of an underlying problem. The unsettling increase of suicides in the last 100 years clearly indicates a social issue rather than a biological one, so we keep asking: where did it go wrong? What is it about the modern world that makes us so prone to misery, despite all obvious improvements in the quality of life?

One pair of clear offenders is the constant stress and pressure as we keep aiming higher and higher, both as humanity and as individuals. Fewer standards in education and work may mean more creativity, but it also means the absence of limits, which leaves us one-on-one with the most brutal critic: ourselves. There was a time when getting straight A’s in school or spending 40 hours a week behind the desk was an all-clear to be satisfied with your performance. Now, even the sky is not the limit, not with so much space above it.

Another commonly mentioned cause is the fall of tightly-knit local communities. Long ago, we used to spend time surrounded by the same group of people, relying on their support throughout the life and slowly building meaningful relationships, but that changed when urbanization and globalization kicked in. Today, we move from place to place, trading dozens of neighbors for millions of strangers, connected to everybody yet no one in particular, and that can feel lonelier than ever.

Loneliness is not the only hidden disadvantage of being interconnected. “What we see thriving is essentially a culture of comparison,” says Hethel O’Black, a writer and columnist. “We have instantaneous access to other people’s stories, and it doesn’t even matter what kind of stories they are. If it’s a bad one, we lament how imperfect and full of tragedies our existence is, but if it’s a success story, we get envious and worry about being failures, managing to take the worst of both worlds. It’s also pretty funny how people try to fight it with the very same thing. They want to appreciate simple stuff more, so they dig up a tale or two about some hapless chaps who died from starvation, and then they joke about first-world problems all self-deprecatingly. They call it ‘perspective’, but what they actually do is more comparing.”

Of course, in the ideal world these problems would be addressed by simply adopting the right attitude and forming realistic expectations. Some believe that mere spreading of awareness can take us a long way. “Unless you are lost in depression-induced thinking – and there are reliable medications for that – rationalizing your troubles is a very powerful technique,” says Roux. “It turns issues from scary mythical beasts to clear obstacles with possible solutions. And where there is a possibility of a solution, there can be no suicide-inducing hopelessness.”

Some, however, feel less optimistic. “It’s the fundamental human nature described in three words: we want more,” says O’Black. “One might say our intense wanting stays the same no matter how much we get, but that would be incorrect; it actually gets progressively worse. Every success, every achievement contributes to our appetite. And, considering our penchant for achievements, it won’t change anytime soon. I think it’s time we accept a simple fact: making the world better won’t necessarily make it happier.”</Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">Time travel could be possible within the next few years, claims Denny Taslim, a person who may have built the world’s first working prototype of a time machine.

A lone inventor not affiliated with any corporation, Taslim attracted international attention to his garage in Jakarta this April when he was making a potato disappear and then reappear on a table nearby precisely 4 minutes 40 seconds later, seemingly teleporting it through time and space. At first, it was discarded as a cheap magic trick, but while numerous debunkers were struggling to no avail, Denny shared his invention online, and the phenomenon was replicated by two other independent groups of researchers. Now, after three months of ceaseless experimenting, Taslim has made visible progress – and shares his optimism with the world.

“I think I know how to control duration and distance,” he explains enthusiastically, “albeit there are upper limits. It is only forward in time, and only potatoes, like it requires a very specific chemical composition or something… but it’s definitely the same potato; I tried to carve images, and they are preserved perfectly. It’s also not just becoming invisible – if I move it 30 minutes forward, then 30 minutes later it reappears in exactly the same state, unaffected by time. I can’t explain it all scientifically yet, but I have a number of theories, and I’m constantly trying things out. Considering that none of this was here 6 months ago, I think in a couple of years we may be transporting animals or even other people.”

Some argue that the young man has yet to demonstrate any real proof of his achievements. “Do you know how many people have already ‘created’ a time machine just to get their 15 minutes in the spotlight? Dozens in my lifetime alone,” points out Andrew Wu, the CEO of Biotec Engineering. “I think we should remain skeptical. Scientific community relies on questioning everything, and the bigger the claim is, the harder you need to scrutinize it. I mean, don’t get me wrong, the kid’s got talent. But whether it’s in doing science or hiding potatoes, I can’t say.”

Mister Wu does have a point: our recent history is filled with urban legends that proved to be hoaxes, misinterpretations, or a little bit of both. In 2001, a self-appointed time traveler named John Titor appeared on the internet and made a number of predictions about the future, none of which came true. In 2019, another man said he developed a real flux capacitor but specified that it required the speed of 488 mph, not 88 mph, and was unable to find an airplane to test his invention. In 2039, three separate persons came up with allegedly working time machines – built out of a laptop, a washing machine, and a headphone set respectively.

“At the moment, we cannot confirm or deny the truthfulness of Mr. Taslim’s claims,” says Liliana Kowalski, a media relations manager at LIFE+. “Our leading theory is that he stumbled upon a natural phenomenon that has nothing to do with time traveling but exhibits visually similar results under these specific circumstances. The good news is that, while working with Denny, we found his knowledge of the subject matter to be extremely impressive, and we already offered him a position at our physics division. Breakthroughs or not, we believe that his valuable input will help our current team and lead to many new exciting possibilities.”

Regardless, it is hard to deny that news like this are capturing our imagination without fail. For decades, time traveling remained among the most alluring yet unrealistic realms of science fiction, but now that its cousin Immortality has started to arrive, people are ready to suspend their disbelief and consider the impossible.

“Oh, Denny, he was always a smart one,” says Edi Basuki, Taslim’s childhood friend. “Built a robot dog when he was 14. Built a quantum computer when he was 15… that one didn’t seem to work though. Loved his potatoes. I’m more of a veggie guy, myself. I recon things like cucumbers would be easier to teleport, since they are basically just water. Hey, is LIFE+ still hiring?”

Whatever the future holds for Taslim and his resourceful neighbors, one thing is clear: the world is willing to hear more.</Piece>
		</News>
	</Issue>
	
	<Issue>
		<Date>Wednesday, July 22, 2048</Date>
		<News>
			<Piece Type="0" Title="FULL-TIME CITIZENS" Subtitle="On the ever-growing power of corporations">Andy McKnight is traveling light. His miniature suitcase holds only bare necessities: medicine, first-aid supplies, underwear, socks, a couple of shirts. He spent the last 5 months in South America, moving from country to country, never staying in one place for more than a week. Now he’s boarding a supersonic jet at Buenos Aires International Airport. In 3 hours, he will cross the Atlantic; in 5, land in Munich for a brief visit to his employer’s European headquarters. From there, it’s a quick hour-long flight to Moscow, where he will work until the end of the year. Then, he will return to the head office in Hong Kong… until the company needs him on the road again.

He passes endless immigration booths like relics of a bygone age. He was born in Scotland, raised in England, lived in Spain, Nigeria, Australia, and Indonesia. He spent enough time in the United States to apply for permanent residence. But all those countries don’t exist for him, not really. He’s a citizen of LIFE+.

The rise of corporate power has been a fruitful topic for decades now, but it’s only recently that a new realization started to sink in: these giants have become countries in their own right. Granted, they don’t give you a passport when signing a contract, but between countless employee benefits they provide and endless deals they secure with actual governments, it’s hard to argue that old-school citizenship can appear somewhat insignificant. LIFE+ and their latest renewal-driven expansion are headlining the trend, but names like R&amp;D&amp;R, Panlight Group, or SGGI are not far behind.

“Whatever part of the world I find myself in, they provide pretty much everything I need or will need in life,” says McKnight. “Housing, healthcare, insurance, retirement plan, daycare, hotel stays… they either pay for it or own it altogether. The only thing I have to do in return is to ensure that I work as hard as possible.”

Of course, opinions differ on whether this is actually a good thing. Many are worried about profit-driven entities gaining so much influence over people’s lives. Businesses’ primary focus is money, they say; they view employees as resources, and throw them away when they’re no longer contributing to the revenue. Some go as far as to call it a modern form of slavery, where workers are forced to agree to any conditions because their entire life depends on having the job.

“I was told that they’re cutting costs for the new projects, and I am no longer needed in this department,” says Yvonne Janssen, a former researcher at LIFE+ math division who had a first-hand experience with the dark side of corporate employment this May. “I could either agree to the new terms or terminate my contract. The former meant transferring to a local medical center and working as an analyst there for half of my current salary. The latter meant having no place to live, because my apartment is their property.”

The manner of delivery, explains Janssen, added insult to injury. “It was so sudden and impersonal. One day, they treat me almost like a family: we chat, laugh, and discuss all the exciting stuff we’ll do together. Next day, they don’t even talk to me; they just send me an updated version of my employment contract and avert their eyes. The best response I could squeeze out was an awkward ‘well, you know how it goes…’ But I don’t know how it goes. If you don’t care, why pretend in the first place? And if you do, then at least have a dignity to properly break the news.”

Janssen’s case is not unique: one can find a number of stories involving equally questionable behavior. Some employees take their matters to court, hoping for justice – but what they frequently find instead is a long, arduous, and stressful experience. Litigations can last for months and months as both sides drown in red tape while trying to figure out whether the law was actually broken. Bureaucracy has always been the favorite buddy of unpleasant business, and apparently it’s not planning to lose ground.

Part of the problem seems to stem from the state of modern legislation, which some tend to describe as “a lawyer’s worst nightmare.” “Every megacorporation is trying to get a special treatment from every major government and vice versa, which is not helping,” tells us Ethan Taylor, an attorney from the US Office of Legal Counsel. “We worked so hard towards clarity and transparency, but now it’s turning into pages of clauses and asterisks again, since rules might apply to you differently depending on who you work for. It’s such a mess, expert software is the only thing helping us to keep it in check. Some even say that corporations want it this way, because, you know, they’re the ones who are selling that software.”

It is hard to say whether companies are willingly abusing the situation or simply making mistakes (one is bound to make some mistakes when running such a massive business). Then again, some believe that nothing good can come from big businesses in the first place. For Larry Evans, a veteran antitrust activist and union member, this is a process that started long ago; a process he fought hard but still had to witness. “There was a time when our elected officials could influence corporations,” he says. “They could break monopolies, prevent mergers, place embargos… but today, it’s too late. Corporations distracted us; lulled us into sleep with dozens of names on supermarket shelves, all of which were controlled by one manufacturer. And when we tried to wake up, they were already too powerful. They didn’t need governments anymore.”

“There was a time when we remembered the basics,” laments Evans. “Fair competition sparks innovation. Power should be equally distributed within society. Workers should have freedom to choose their own path instead of getting aggressively hired and removed from the market for the rest of their lives… but not anymore. Today, the world is a playground for big companies, and millions of bright young minds are tricked to play along. You say you enjoy the benefits, or like to travel the world. But is it really a fair deal? Do they deserve your citizenship when they can change the terms as they please, or even revoke it altogether?”

Corporations themselves consider this pessimistic view outdated. “There is a common misconception,” explains Sabine Wagner, a public relations specialist at R&amp;D&amp;R, “that ‘doing business’ means ‘chasing immediate profits, and damn the consequences’. We agree that entrepreneurship was dominated by such mindset in the past, and it caused a lot of economic trouble. But it’s been a long time since we realized how short-sighted this approach is. Being greedy and egotistical helps nobody. We couldn’t be parasites on the body of this planet – parasites eventually kill their host, and there is only one host for all of us. We embraced our social and environmental responsibilities, and we never looked back. We don’t want to bleed people dry and force them into corners – we want to make them happy and build lasting relationships. Trust me, it’s in our own best interests.”

“They didn’t get this far by being jerks, that much we can guarantee you,” agrees Katy Lee, assessment manager at the Fair Labor Association. “Everybody knows how finicky our motivation centers can be, and how many conditions must be met to remain consistent in any complicated endeavor. You can force people to serve coffee, or wipe tables, or repeat some other clear pattern for 16 hours a day. You can’t force them to be creative and inventive for 16 hours a day. When you aim as high as LIFE+, there’s simply no other choice. You need to pamper your talent, and do everything possible to keep them happy.”

Statistics also appear to be on the companies’ side. Ten years ago, when the big names neatly divided the market into spheres of monopolistic influence, it was common to be doubtful and skeptical, but today, people are slowly letting go of their distrust. According to the recent surveys and online ratings, LIFE+ boasts 88 percent of approval, with 76% of customers commending the high quality of their goods and services, and 59% feeling positive about the company’s role as the leading force in scientific research and technological innovation. Biotec Engineering, despite ranking lowest among the 10 biggest corporations, still sports a decent 65% approval rating. As for the employees, 93% are satisfied with their working conditions, with 82% saying their contract terms are fair, and 69% feeling their job is secure. Last but not least, 87% of former employees describe their experience as positive, while only 0.22% feel mistreated, wronged, or deceived by their employer, marking incidents like Janssen’s as clear (though still unfortunate) minority.

“I like working for LIFE+,” says McKnight. “I come in touch with many teams, and occasionally we might not get along, but the right spirit is always there. It’s always about improving lives with technology, and making the world a better place… I’m amazed how good this company is at setting the mood across every division, despite being so huge. I didn’t really study my rights, and I don’t remember much about my contract either, but I never felt like I have to. I mean, if worst comes to worst, what can I do, anyway? I’m just a guy, while they are the most powerful thing on the planet. But this singular thing exists only on paper; in reality, it is made of many individuals. I saw them, worked with them, and they’re… people, you know? Folks just like the rest of us. They do their jobs, live their lives, and try to do the right thing. I mean, I haven’t met everybody… maybe somewhere upstairs there’s someone who has so much power, they completely lost their humanity. But I don’t think so. I guess I just decided to believe that.”

Putting your trust in others is a noble thing to do, but it sounds risky to simply rely on the corporate goodwill. The good news? We don’t have to. In a sense, we are already covered by that one thing which enforces transparency by default – the internet. “You can see a correlation when you compare the ratings from different years,” explains Lee. “Whenever the amount of people who are mistreated goes up, general approval goes down. But you don’t have to employ statistics to spot that; just go online and look around. Look how much attention is attracted to the cases of corporate abuse, and how strongly common folks support the victims. Our mess of a legal system may not help Janssen, but society is still on her side. And corporations rely on society; they need its approval to function. Every unhappy employee costs them, and costs dearly. They ARE accountable – to each and every one of us.”

“The great thing about it is that the system's already in place,” she continues. “It’s not about companies making conscious steps towards becoming more transparent – it’s about being forced to become transparent, because the world already is. It is incredibly hard to keep secrets when the Earth is one giant interconnected network. We just need to recognize it and use the hell out of it, because that’s the way to go. That is how you enforce equality and hold the powerful in check. That is how you get to keep democracy and freedom in the 21st century. And if there are more social problems to face in the near future, let’s make sure we remember it.”

But that comes later. Today, Andy McKnight is crossing the Atlantic. He will rise 21,000 meters above the ground and fly three times faster than the speed of sound. He will look through the window and see the curvature of the Earth, blue glow of the atmosphere, and the space above it. And his life – although unpredictable and prone to changes – will be an alright one to live.</Piece>
			<Piece Type="1" Title="WE’RE UNEMPLOYED,[nl]BUT THAT’S OKAY" Subtitle="by Natalie Seifridge">Let’s talk about a problem that doesn’t have to be a problem. I’ll say it straight away, before boring you with any “ifs” and “buts”: you don’t need a job to survive in this world anymore. You don’t need money, and therefore, you don’t need a job. And by “survive,” I don’t mean “afford bare necessities to stay alive.” I mean live a comfortable and eventful life.

Now, chances are you had to pay the bills last month and therefore know that it’s not entirely true. But it can be true, and really soon. The tools are right there – we only need to recognize them.

Let’s face it: unemployment rates have been steadily growing for decades and show no signs of slowing down. We call it crisis, we call it recession; we talk about fixing the economy, adapting it to the modern world, even though nobody knows how the hell it’s supposed to be done in the first place. But it’s all water under the bridge. The keyword? Automation. People are unemployed because there is no need to employ them. The machines can do better and cheaper. Where hundreds of workers were required before, now one person with a computer would do.

Is it a scary thing? For sure. Is it bad thing? No. It can be the best thing, if only we play our cards right. The point is to look at the situation broadly. It’s natural for social progress to lag behind the technological one, but we need to make sure it doesn’t stray too far. Profound changes have to be addressed in equally profound ways.

Should every person have a job? What about those who are unable to work? People with disabilities? We give them social benefits. We care for them, because it’s the right thing to do, but also because we can; we have government and taxes for this sort of thing. The whole point of having a society is to ensure that everyone can live a good life, even if those in power need to sacrifice a bit of their well-being. And now we go out of our way to create more jobs, even when it’s not a sound business solution. But why take the convoluted way? Why sacrifice revenue on a symptom when you can sacrifice it to treat an underlying problem?

Just think about all those wonderful things you have free access to, or have to pay a bare minimum for. Healthcare, education, libraries, internet, entertainment. It depends on where you live, and there are nuances, but the general trend is unmistakable: what once was a luxury can become an expected commodity. So why not go all the way through? Why not take the necessities – stuff we need to earn money for in the first place – and try to make them essentially free? After all, things cannot be free only because there is a cost associated with them. Food must have a price because farmers worked hard to cultivate and grow it. But what if machines do it, and the process is streamlined and optimized until it costs almost nothing at all? We can use the very automation that drives unemployment to render it obsolete.

I’m sure the idea must be uncomfortable to a lot of folks. After all, hard and honest labor has been a cornerstone of society for thousands of years. When billions of people find themselves with so much free time on their hands, where does it leave us? Isn’t it too dangerous? Wouldn’t that leave too much time for conflicts, violence, wars and other humanity's favorite pastimes? But most wars are fought over resources; they come from scarcity, not abundance. Some wars are ideological, yet once again, ideology thrives when commodities are insufficient. It’s easy to get distracted by righteous indignation on an empty stomach – in fact, you’d want to. On a full stomach? Not so much.

It’s okay, people. I know it’s scary, but it’s okay. It’s all right to find ourselves in the world where you are not required to work – where you are not required to do anything, really; where you can just live. We’re still going to do science, make art, invent things – the need to create goes much deeper than financial well-being. But the only pressure will come from within, and that’s how it should be, really. Everyone should be free to live their life in a way they want. If it sounds like utopia for you, too good to be true – rest assured, it won’t be; but it doesn’t have to be a train wreck either. At the very least, we should try.

&lt;i>*A seasoned engineer and a captivating public speaker, &lt;b>Natalie Seifridge&lt;/b> studies social implications of technological innovation, providing valuable perspective on the tangled mess known as “global economy.” To learn more about a world without jobs, as well as current regional experiments in universal basic income, visit &lt;b>post.scarcity.society.&lt;/b>&lt;/i></Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">On Monday morning, 27 church buildings across Italy have re-opened their doors, despite the fact that none of them has seen regular service for decades. Dubbed “redundant churches,” these former places of worship were once closed due to the lack of attendees and have been used as offices, residential properties, education centers, art galleries, or even indoor climbing gyms – but now the Roman Catholic Church is reclaiming the lost ground. However, they don’t want to simply restore traditions; on the contrary, the old-new locations bring enough changes to be viewed as decidedly modern.

“I think it’s our own fault that this place was closed for so long,” says Giacomo Moretti, a priest from the church of San Antonio in Florence. “The church fell out of touch with its followers, didn’t adapt to the new world. When people wanted feelings, it gave them rigid rituals. But we don’t intend to repeat the same mistakes twice. This time, we have very different priorities.”

This claim seems to be supported by the signs at the entrance, which concentrate on what you can do rather than what you should not. The doors are open 24 hours a day; no dress code is imposed; pets and robots are welcome. Inside, sermons of bishops are streaming on large screens, while net access points are inviting to learn about Christianity with a selected collection of books, films, and VR simulations.

According to Moretti, the new plan is to be more inclusive and outsider-oriented rather than serve as a gathering place for the already convinced. “We don’t want to dominate anybody’s life,” he explains. “There are so many interesting secular pastimes these days, few people have time or desire to visit church every Sunday, and we respect that. We also don’t aim to build close-knit communities; our hectic urban way of living makes that pretty hard to pull off. What we can do, however, is to make this place friendly to newcomers. People who search for something new. People who are sightseeing or simply passing by. We can show them our core values and beliefs in a modern, engaging way.”

The move has attracted criticism from both ends of the spectrum, as more conservative believers oppose the innovations, while some non-affiliated keep wondering whether we still need churches at all. “This is a compromise taken way too far,” argues Brother Fernando, a fellow Catholic from Spain. “I know they do it for attention, but Christianity has standards. If you want to educate, start a school; if you want to see animals, visit a zoo… but churches are for worship. Quiet, dignified worship.”

“I don’t see any point in trying again something that naturally died down, even if you change a few things,” says blogger Jessica Green. “Maybe the online stuff is enough. Or maybe organized religion is just not so important anymore. Maybe now, as we better see the sheer complexity of the world, we can understand that claiming to know so much and be so certain about the nature of all things is just ridiculous. I mean, if you like your way of thinking, just distill it into a philosophy or a branch of psychology or something… but drop this Heaven/Hell stuff and other afterlife hogwash. Nobody knows what happens after, okay? Humanity is old enough to accept that.”

Still, if a single week is any indication, the experiment can be called a moderate success: most of the 27 churches have been visited by hundreds of people, and some of the passersby seem genuinely interested in the new approach. “It definitely feels less imposing,” says Wang Min, a tourist. “I usually go inside churches just to gaze at the architecture, but this has been educational.”

“Religion is not some kind of immutable rock, standing its ground while everything else moves forward,” adds Moretti. “It’s a complex system that changes and evolves, just like our society and our perception of the world do. But when all is said and done, and I come back to the very basics… when I read the teachings of the Christ, I am reminded that his message is every bit as relevant and important as it was 2000 years ago. We should be compassionate and kind to each other. We should practice empathy and forgiveness, even for those who hurt us most. We should spend our time learning to love, not chasing the ghosts of personal desires. When I follow the way of Jesus, I feel at peace. So that’s what we’re trying to share… if somebody walks out of this church with a little bit more peace inside them, our work is not in vain.”</Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">Tasteful Museums Group, a non-profit behind many of the world’s food and beverage museums, is launching a new temporary exhibition revolving around coffee serving traditions. For nine weeks, visitors can enjoy the authentic taste of the famous brewed drink while being immersed in a variety of customs, ranging from age-old ceremonies to inventions of modern-day baristas.

“Today, many people drink coffee for effect rather than enjoyment,” says Omid Hosseini, a curator of Grand Bazaar History Museum in Istanbul. “They swallow it quickly at breakfast or sip it on the go as they carry on with their day. We’d like to remind that, should you only slow down, you can find so much more. You can find a complete, meaningful experience and rich, fascinating traditions.”

Hardcore coffee lovers will no doubt be pleased by the level of detail and the feel of cultural importance common to the ceremonies of Ethiopia, the birthplace of coffee cultivation. “The entire process happens right in front of you,” explains Siyane Elias, a creative consultant for the exhibition and the owner of a coffee shop in Addis Ababa. “The beans are roasted in a pan over a small brazier, and the aromatic smoke is guaranteed to fill you with anticipation. Small snacks like peanuts are frequently served, and incense is burned for additional fragrance. When the beans are ready, they are grinded by hand and brewed three times, resulting in three separate rounds for everyone participating, with enough time to socialize in-between. But it is bigger than that – it’s a sign of hospitality, a staple of daily life, a way to hold important meetings and build lasting relationships. It is even said that the third round gives you a blessing.”

Modern coffee-makers have some tricks up their sleeve as well, and they are more than ready to compete for the visitors’ love against centuries of tradition. “Great coffee, like all latest human achievements, is a synergy between man and machine,” says Alexandra Dolgina, two-time winner of the World Barista Championship. “The machines I use are very smart and precise, giving me the perfect dosage of every ingredient and helping to monitor the process with sensors. But how to go from good espressos to the best espressos in the world? How to add creativity to your signature drinks? How to give your customer a unique personalized experience after just a few words of exchange? There are no algorithms for this, so that’s where I come in and do my thing.”

To promote the exhibition, Dolgina has agreed to travel around the world and spend 1-2 days at every location to personally serve the visitors her award-winning creations. “We start at the US West Coast, and then I’ll be literally traversing the globe all the way to Tokyo,” she mentions. “So yeah, it’s going to be a crazy couple of months, but I like the idea. I want everyone to experience the magic, not just the people who visit those fancy expensive cafes where I usually end up working.”

But even the most typical espresso bar can surprise you with customs if you’re willing to be a little curious, argues Hosseini. “For example, many serve espresso with a glass of sparkling water on the side, and there is a simple practical reason for that, as caffeine can mildly dehydrate you. But the interesting bit is how much variety it introduces. First, you can use the water to cleanse your palate and fully appreciate the flavor. Then, you take your first sip of espresso – and then, the choice is all yours. If you like it enough, and you want to keep the aftertaste, you can finish the water right away and then enjoy your coffee. But if you don’t, you can use the water at the end again for cleansing. It just shows you how much thought was put over the years even into the smallest of things,” he concludes.

The exhibition opens next Monday at over 40 locations worldwide, with a free virtual reality substitute available online. Visit tasteful.museums.group to see timetables and admission prices, buy tickets, or get the VR app.</Piece>
		</News>
	</Issue>
	
	<Issue>
		<Date>Thursday, July 23, 2048</Date>
		<News>
			<Piece Type="0" Title="BACK TO THE NUMBERS" Subtitle="World Summit attendees reflect on the state of the world">As the days of summer heat draw to a close across the cities of Europe, so do the heated debates of the UN World Summit in Berlin, a biennial three-week-long marathon where thousands of people gather to discuss the state of humanity and the ways to improve it. Among this year's results are the new space exploration program, further plans to combat climate change, and a detailed strategy of working towards Global Goals 2060 (our fourth set of quantifiable targets since the Millennium Development Goals were introduced in 2000). The meetings themselves will continue over the weekend, but, as usual, most of the participants use this time to take a break, look back, and remind us of the job already done.

For one, 2048 can be celebrated as the 10th anniversary of ending absolute poverty. Back in 1996, more than 40% of the world’s population was living on less than $1 a day, which meant severe deprivation of basic human needs such as food, safe drinking water, health, and shelter. By 2010, this number was reduced to 20%; by 2030 – to 10%; in 2038, it went below the target level of 3%. Today, it is estimated that only 0.7% experience life below the poverty line, which happens in different parts of the globe due to economic fluctuations rather than in some specific poor regions. A common companion of poverty – hunger – proved more resilient due to a combination of financial crises and climate-change-related droughts, but went on a quick decline in the late 20s, and now troubles only 1.9% of people.

Diseases that once killed millions – polio, tuberculosis, malaria, HIV – are either completely eradicated or reduced to a minimum. Containment measures have been advanced greatly, which allowed us to avoid serious epidemics during the past 30 years, even amidst the rise in emerging infectious diseases. New pathogens and their potential outbreaks remain a threat, but the world is as ready for them as it once was ready for a nuclear war.

Child mortality dropped by 66% between 1990 and 2025 and by 63% more between 2025 and 2045 (from an average of 90 per 1000 births to 30 to 11) thanks to universal access to clean water, malnutrition prevention, affordable vaccination, and other vast healthcare improvements in low-income countries during the period. In turn, life expectancy rose from 71.0 to 80.1 in 30 years. Fewer child deaths also allowed to significantly push back the looming danger of overpopulation, as more and more people gained access to proper family planning and chose to have fewer babies.

Clean energy is becoming increasingly commonplace. Last year, 56% of global electricity supply came from renewable sources, 15% from nuclear power, and only 28% from fossil fuels (compared to 80% in 2015). Consequently, 12.2 gigatonnes of carbon dioxide were emitted, which is almost 4 times less than the peak value of 45.6 gigatonnes from 2026. Current concentration of CO2 remains at 462 ppm, an all-time high, due to its nasty habit to stay in the atmosphere for decades, but the rise has been slowly grinding to a halt, and we’ll probably see our first yearly reduction within a decade. Global surface temperature shows a similar trend; 2.4 °C above pre-industrial levels is the hottest it should get in this century. Further hard work to solidify the progress is definitely in order, but we have a good chance to avoid the most serious consequences, experts agree.

Last but not least, violence is at an all-time low. The number of homicides was gradually reduced from 468,000 in 2010 to 197,000 in 2045; fighting organized crime, restricting access to firearms, and improving socio-economic stability all contributed to the improvement. War-related statistics fared even better, with the number of conflicts waged around the world dropping from 32 to 7, and the number of deaths by warfare reduced by almost 80%. Cases of rape were cut in half, cases of domestic violence – by 45%.

And although the sign of any self-respecting futuristic city – flying cars – are still far away from mass production, self-driving cars are clearly the next best thing. In 2010, road traffic injuries caused an estimated 1.25 million deaths, with 90% of accidents attributed to human factors such as fatigue, distraction, driving under the influence, or exceeding speed limit. Additional safety measures managed to moderately improve the situation, but it’s only after automated vehicles became commonplace that we saw a dramatic drop in numbers. Last year, fewer than 500 fatalities have occurred on the road. Furthermore, the switch to electric motors allowed us to reduce greenhouse emissions from combustion engines almost to a zero. 

But quantifiable change is not the only thing the Summit’s visitors are interested in today; they also discuss shifts in our perception. What did we think about the world and each other in the past? What do we think about the world and each other today? Did it change – and if so, did it help?

According to Nikki Hardingham, communication officer at the World Health Organization, reduction of prejudice did more for world peace that any political meeting in this century, and we have globalization and equality to thank for it. “An inherent danger of the divided world is that it encourages stereotyping,” she explains. “We took entire regions populated by millions and talked about them solely through the lenses of their problems. Sub-Saharan Africa was poor, Middle East – violent, China – polluted and heavily censored, America – divided and consumed by outrage… it was so easy to forget that people in other countries were, well, people. That they had families, friends, hopes, dreams, just like the rest of us. But, little by little, that started to change. We focused on our similarities, not on our differences, and worked together to ensure that less fortunate could experience these similarities as well. Today, the planet is one. It doesn’t mean that cultural diversity is gone – it just means you are free to experience life in 21st century, regardless of your place of birth.”

Li Yan, professor of social psychology from Tsinghua University, fully supports the sentiment. “It was an age-old, tried-and-tested narrative: us versus them. We turned the TV on, and it showed us enemies; villains from across the border who threaten our very way of life. Politicians used it to distract people from more complicated issues, but there was also something comforting about the idea. If we are surrounded by villains, then we must be the heroes, and who doesn’t want to be a hero of the story? But the new generation adopted another narrative. We’re not heroes, we’re not special, and that’s okay. There are people who disagree with us, who have very different values, and that’s okay too. We can still work together. Progress is not a zero-sum game.”

But even though we became less apprehensive of each other, we are still pretty anxious about our future. According to various surveys, up to 35% of people today believe that the world is actually getting worse, not better, while another 20% feel that our good fortune will not last. Some even bring up ancient civilizations that had impressive peaks but eventually crumbled. “Optimists these days are like suicide jumpers who leap from a tall building and scream ‘Everything is fine!’ halfway through,” says author Oliver Hoffman. “Good things happen gradually, but bad things can happen all at once. It won’t take much to flush all of our advancements down the toilet.”

Pessimists are definitely entitled to their opinion, yet some worry how negativity can affect our actions. Hardingham believes that this “perceived decadence” should be recognized as a separate issue, or else sentiments about crumbling civilizations may become self-fulfilling prophecies. “The first half of this century was defined by what we now consider basic human needs,” she says. “But as we move beyond that and delve deeper into the mysteries of the universe – and our own human psyche – I think different problems will start to appear; problems that may look weird and irrational at first but will prove just as important to solve. And believing in ourselves will be more important than ever.”

The easiest way to do so? Go back to the numbers. “We don’t want to criticize anyone for their views,” explains Hardingham. “Our worries are valid, even if they don’t align with data… I know I have my share of those. But a simple reminder can help. So please, take a look at these statistics and remember: the efforts of humanity are not in vain. The world is getting objectively better.”</Piece>
			<Piece Type="1" Title="HOW MASS SURVEILLANCE[nl]SILENTLY WON" Subtitle="by Hethel O’Black">Ever heard of Big Brother? There was this book written by a guy almost 100 years ago, and he was one of the characters. He turned into quite a symbol: a synonym for abuse of power, a boogeyman for adults. He was like an evil mastermind, constantly plotting in secret to steal away our democratic freedoms. People would mention Big Brother when their civil liberties were being violated – like too many cameras on the street, or too much personal data gathered online, or some other totalitarian smell in the air. But that was quite some time ago. These days, nobody is afraid of Big Brother anymore. These days, we’re basically pals.

Looking back at it, you might rightfully wonder: why on earth did we befriend someone like this? Isn’t privacy a good thing? Don’t we need personal space to live normal lives? Do we really want corporations and governments to trace our every step? Why would we just ignore the warnings of the writer? Perhaps we were tricked to do so. Perhaps this is some kind of conspiracy; a plan carefully executed by vile men who rule us from the shadows. Alas, my friend, you’re wrong.

Like, can you imagine that mere 40 years the online world was a cradle of anonymity? We talked on forums and imageboards using nicknames and avatars, and there was no way to figure out who we are in real life or where we live. Do you know that, as far as technical capabilities go, the last part is still true? That’s right, the basic technology remains unchanged. To this day, it is impossible to reliably pinpoint your physical location based on the traces of your online presence – unless, of course, you voluntarily disclose identifying information. The internet was not designed with mass surveillance in mind.

But that’s not a problem anymore, is it? When social networks arrived, they offered us something clearly superior: to upload our photos and talk using real names with people who live nearby anyway. Anonymity was branded as a domain of bullies and trolls; an inherently dangerous condition that can only bring out the worst in people. Your online accounts should be like passports, they said – unified, secure, reliable, and oh-so-very, very real. And like passports they are now. Who needs complicated engineering solutions when you can just convince people to play along? Wait, did I say “convince people”? I’m sorry, that’s not entirely accurate. That implies someone on the outside, like Big Brother, was influencing our opinion and steering it in the right direction. Sadly, that’s not the case.

There was, of course, a small matter of those who didn’t bother using the internet and therefore was immune to tracking, but the Internet of Things certainly rectified this issue. It’s not that everything is online – everything is seamlessly online. A small microchip on a bus can log commute habits of every passenger, but nobody is obligated to advertise its presence. That old-school grumpy grandpa who lives next door to you might think he has his privacy intact, but corporations can see his every step just the same. A lot of the time, people are not even aware that they’re connected to the network, but they are. We are always connected. There is no escape.

Here’s a funny thing: there was this other guy who once leaked classified information about his government’s exercises in global monitoring. He pointed out that, ironically, those exercises were fairly useless in terms of practical benefits. Like, they didn’t help to fight terrorism, or improve day-to-day safety of the citizens, because there was no way to separate valuable clues from useless noise. The agency in question was just hoarding personal data, like a dragon from a fairy tale, but it didn’t have algorithms sophisticated enough to properly analyze it.

Being a good Big Brother is hard work, you know. It’s not enough to spy – you also need to process your findings. And even if somebody can do it on a national scale, doing it worldwide is a whole different matter; the infrastructure alone would give you a headache. But hey, good news: it’s thirty years later, and we can finally congratulate the powers-that-be on the job well done.

Did you know that LIFE+ has a giant database that contains personal information on almost every single human being on this planet, stored on a server farm somewhere? You probably do; it’s not even a secret. It logs your every action, from the moment you’re born to the day you die. It records every conversation you have, then assigns it 2 IDs for quick future reference. Screw top-secret military bases and nuclear weapon storage sites – this is the most secure facility in the world. This is where the big guns are.

It is not easy to maintain this database. There are hundreds of amazing software engineers, working day and night, typing away at their keyboard projections, designing incredibly complicated algorithms. They don’t think they’re doing anything wrong. They don’t laugh maniacally like comic book villains either. They do it for our own safety and security, to maintain order and peace. You probably think it’s not their fault. Clearly, those ordinary folks are being brainwashed and manipulated just like the rest of us, oblivious to the vile implications of their state-of-the-art programming. Don’t blame them, blame Big Brother, you say. You are, yet again, wrong.

And it’s not like I told you anything secret. Like, yeah, LIFE+ is understandably sketchy on the details, but it’s not classified information. That’s the best part: people know all this, and they are totally cool with it. Thirty years ago, everyone would’ve freaked out, but not today. There has been a fundamental shift in conscience. You might want to call this shift orchestrated. Unfortunately, you’d be wrong.

Do you know why you are always wrong? Because there is no Big Brother. There never was. It’s all made up. It’s a non-existent entity brought up to justify things we don’t approve but still secretly want. It’s easy to blame stuff on a handful of powerful individuals, but the truth is, we – the masses – wished for it all along. Evil geniuses do not operate in vacuum; they’re just a reflection of our collective insanity.

So if you want to take away one thing, take this: we lost our privacy because it’s just too bloody convenient. There was no conspiracy, no manipulation, and no trickery. Nobody forced you into giving up your democratic freedoms; nobody took away your God-given rights. We threw them away ourselves. We wanted our everyday live to be more easy and comfortable – we made it so, and damn the consequences. And it’s the consequences we have to live with.

&lt;i>*Knowledgeable, passionate, and brutally honest, &lt;b>Hethel O’Black&lt;/b> is a kind of man who will keep our feet on the ground even as our overly excited heads drift in the clouds. To read official terms, conditions, agreements, and privacy considerations of LIFE+ telecommunications services, visit &lt;b>life.plus.legal.&lt;/b>&lt;/i></Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">A team of marine explorers has managed to drill 5 kilometers into the Earth’s mantle and retrieve multiple valuable rock samples, says the latest report from the Scientific Drilling Project.

Part of an ongoing international effort known as Deep Earth Exploration Program (or DEEP for short), it involved parking a specially constructed drilling ship in the northern Pacific Ocean, lowering equipment to the seabed, and then boring a narrow shaft through 7 km of oceanic crust (which is pretty thin compared to the usual 30-60 km of continental crust) and further 5 km into the outer mantle, for a total of 12 km. This sets a new record for the depth of mantle penetration and also ties with Kola Superdeep Borehole (which was drilled on land by Soviet Union between 1970 and 1989) as the deepest artificial point on Earth. The impressive feat was achieved by 6 separate expeditions over the course of 11 years.

“This ugly deformed rock is worth more than a mountain of pure gold to geology,” says co-chief scientist Kungawo Joubert as he gingerly holds a roundish piece of the mantle about 20 cm in diameter. “For decades, our knowledge of the Earth’s inner workings was coming through indirect sources. We studied seismic waves, analyzed little bits ejected by volcanoes, tried to recreate similar conditions in a lab. We had to rely more on educated guesswork than on hard facts and based entire theories solely on remote observations. But this stuff is pristine. There is no substitute for direct samples.”

The road to the second layer of the planet’s interior was anything but smooth. The US made the first attempt in 1961 – an Earth science equivalent of the Space Race at the time – but dug only 183 m before the project was closed down. In 1997, an expedition in the Indian Ocean had to stop at 1.5 km when their equipment snapped under high winds and plugged the hole. When we the mantle was first reached in 2027, it managed to capture the world’s attention and bring more funding, but every new kilometer of every new hole still proves to be a solid challenge.

Meanwhile, an equally daring project – the world’s first mantle probe – continues to slowly descend toward the center of the Earth. Encased in a sturdy shell that can keep its form under extreme conditions, this small sphere uses nuclear reaction to burn its way through at a rate of about 2.7 km per year, even as the molten rock behind it re-solidifies. Information about the surroundings is picked up by the sensors and transmitted via acoustic vibrations, which are later picked up by seismographs on the surface. The return trip is not included, but this is a small price to pay for going where no probe has gone before.

Linh Thao Tran, a geophysicist at LIFE+ geoscience division, believes that probes like this are the future of deep exploration. “Drilling is good, but you can only dig so far before the hole collapses in on itself,” she explains. “When you’re not bothered to leave a tunnel behind, however, there are no theoretical limitations on how deep you can go. Our current probe won’t go much further than 100 km; eventually, the ever-increasing heat and pressure will be too much for its shell… and when you compare it to the Earth’s radius, 100 km is still barely scratching the surface. But I think, as we analyze the gathered data, we’ll learn more about materials, and build probes that will be even sturdier and sink even faster, and so on, until – who knows? – we may even reach the core.”

Advancement of materials science is not the only practical benefit of these projects – they also help us to understand earthquakes. “Every dangerous earthquake originates either in the upper mantle or in the crust,” says Tran. “If we want to have reliable predictions one day, we’ll need to keep learning about these areas. Naturally, preventing deaths and damage from earthquakes goes far beyond scientific research; it’s a social, economic, and engineering challenge all at the same time. But every bit of knowledge helps.”

Of course, as the scale of our geological endeavors grows bigger, so does our fear of man-induced natural disasters. “Yeah, maybe they’ll predict earthquakes… or maybe they’ll just cause new ones,” shares his worries Agus Riady, a survivor of 2004 Boxing Day tsunami who knows the destructive potential of nature all too well. “I don’t think I’m comfortable with scientists experimenting on the body of our planet. Experiments on human bodies sometimes end badly, right? But if we mess up the Earth’s body, where will we get another one?”

The valid concern raises a non-rhetorical question: what if we could get another one? Perhaps, instead of dissecting our only home, we should focus on finding different places that support life, or try to create habitable areas on the nearby planets?

Interestingly enough, one might prove impossible without the other. According to Adriana Sartini from NASA, our journey inward helps our journey outward, and vice versa. “There is a process called ‘serpentinization’ that happens when mantle rocks interact with the seawater,” she explains. “It creates microscopic holes filled with methane and hydrogen, which microorganisms consume for energy, effectively allowing them to exist in the absence of sunlight. It was the samples from drilling expeditions that gave us a way to study it, and it provided valuable insight into how life can survive under harsh conditions, informing our own operations on Mars. And it’s just one of the examples. Our planet may be unique, but it was formed under the same cosmic rules. The more we understand it, the more we understand the rest of the universe.”

At the moment, there are no definitive plans for another round of drilling, but the DEEP team remains optimistic about further improving their freshly set record.</Piece>
			<Piece Type="2">The first manned mission to Mars won’t launch until at least 2053, says the UN Office for Outer Space Affairs, citing “unacceptable risks to astronauts’ lives” as a reason for yet another delay.

One of the most expensive programs in the history of space exploration, Project Red Planet nevertheless spent the last 8 years in limbo as engineers went through countless iterations and improvements, struggling to guarantee success. According to deputy manager Riko Iwasaki, right now there are no technical limitations to launch within months, but it’s not a chance we’d want to take.

“We keep bumping into small things when we run simulations,” she explains, “a 20% chance of malfunction here, a 10% chance of system overload there… all individually manageable, but if you combine them together, the danger becomes real. We also need to gather more data about potential landing zones in order to minimize the degree of uncertainty regarding Mars itself. It’s true that we take risks like this all the time with regular unmanned programs, but this is the first human spaceflight to Mars we’re talking about. We cannot afford it ending in disaster; the stakes are just too high.”

Despite these arguments, the decision has been criticized as overly-cautious. Some worry that this international effort is getting crippled by safety concerns, while others simply encourage space agencies to “get real.” “Look, you can’t possibly do what no man has done before and expect everything to go without a hitch,” says Robin D’Costa, an aerospace engineer at Panlight Group. “You think they should’ve stopped Columbus from sailing to the New World just because survival was not guaranteed? What about Everest climbers, or Antarctic and Arctic explorers? Pioneering is supposed to be dangerous. Yes, some folks might die. But it would be for a good cause.”

Public frustration is easy to understand: it’s been 79 years since we landed on the Moon, and the next giant leap for mankind feels long overdue. The initial designs of the mission’s spacecraft date back to the early 2010s. Since then, we dug for helium-3 on the lunar surface, developed commercial (albeit very expensive) suborbital flights, and even established a semi-regular asteroid mining operation at the L2 point – but setting foot on the red planet remains an elusive goal.

Some, however, view PRP’s continuous struggles as an inherently good thing. Sending people to different planets is a tremendous challenge, and if we learn that through simulated tragedies rather than real tragedies, all the better. It may also be an unnecessary challenge, since robots provide a safer and much cheaper way of exploring the universe.

“Almost everything we learned about space in this century comes from unmanned missions,” says Alina Morozova, an astrophysicist from Russian Space Agency. “We peered into galaxies billions of light years away, scanned every planet in our solar system, and catalogued most of the dangerous asteroids, all without leaving low-Earth orbit. We automated it, just like we strive to automate any other occupation, especially if it happens in hostile environments. I mean, we don’t talk about sending people into volcanoes or onto the ocean’s floor, right? We talk about robots that can explore them for us. Yet when it comes to space, we insist on going there personally, as far as possible and as soon as possible, just because we theoretically can… never mind that it costs 100 times more than any conceivable probe. I think we’ll be better off spending this money elsewhere.”

As Morozova explains, there is no reason why all of the crew’s proposed activities can’t be carried out by rovers, drones, diggers, and other robotic vehicles while experts operate them remotely from the safety of Earth. Our only unavoidable limitation will be the speed of light, which causes a delay in communications and prevents real-time control (for Mars this delay is between 4 and 24 minutes), but working around it with clever programming might still be easier than planning manned interplanetary journeys.

“There is little scientific value in sending humans to Mars,” agrees Frederick Rangan, professor of theoretical physics from Oxford University. “When people talk excitedly about the importance of this project, they don’t think about science – they think about big headlines and inspirational stories. They bring up the Apollo missions, which were driven by national pride and Cold-War-induced sense of urgency rather than by scientific curiosity. Taking a stroll on the surface of another celestial body does not improve our understanding of the universe; it’s the samples you retrieve, and the observations your make that matter. But robots can do that too. They can do anything we want, really, if only we take time to teach them.”

As for the team behind the project themselves, they prefer to look further ahead. “This is not about ambitions or challenges for us – it’s about recognizing our long-term goals,” says Iwasaki. “One day – whether it’s because of dwindling resources, cosmic disasters, climate change, or something else – we will be forced to leave this planet. It may not happen this century, or next century, or even the century after that, but make no mistake, it will happen. Then, any technology that allows human beings to survive in space will become urgent necessity. As Tsiolkovsky said, Earth is the cradle of humanity… but one cannot remain in the cradle forever."</Piece>
		</News>
	</Issue>
  </List>
</Root>