<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<Root xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
	<ProfileList>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Karl O’Brien&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> suspect A
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 27
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.85 m
Actor and occasional writer. Studied arts at the local university; happy to share his experience as long as it’s being greatly appreciated. Good at perfecting little details and ignoring deadlines. Likes classic literature and obscure art-house films. Maintains the air of sophistication bordering on arrogance.</Profile>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Vivienne Laurent&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> suspect B
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 24
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.81 m
Lead actress alongside the victim. Takes method acting to its logical extreme by constantly impersonating various characters from her favorite fictional stories. Likes sewing, cooking, and exploring the history of geek culture. Utilizes her skill of master cosplayer to provide costumes and makeup for the entire production.
</Profile>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Daniel Wong&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> suspect C
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 24
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.73 m
Newcomer and ambivalent assistant. Absent-minded but easy-going. Tries to study economics at the local university; likes karaoke and late-night parties. Enamored by jobs with benefits and corporate lifestyle. Harbors romantic feelings towards the victim, much to her discomfort.
</Profile>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Anne Marie Hill&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> suspect D
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 26
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.65 m
Set designer and the victim’s childhood friend. Enjoys physical contact with reality, from drawing pen-and-paper sketches to building decorations. Keeps a constant vigil over her friend’s well-being and tries to protect her from stressing out, sometimes to the point of stressing out herself. Has a strained relationship with suspect C.
</Profile>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Cloe Lin&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> suspect E
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 19
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.45 m
Principal writer and eccentric dreamer. Studies electrical engineering at the local university. Considers the meat world inherently boring; wants to relocate to the Antarctic. Enjoys big ideas, transhumanistic values, and reality-bending possibilities. Shows little interest in anything else, including the current incident.
</Profile>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Ashley Simmons&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> victim
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 22
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.67 m
Lead actress and fan’s favorite. Doubles in as the team’s workhorse by always volunteering to do whatever needs to be done. Likes bold colors, interior design, and experiments with hair. Tends to trust people unconditionally, sometimes to her detriment. Subject to suspect C’s awkward and inconsiderate romantic attempts.
</Profile>
		<Profile>&lt;b>Boyd Weber&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Status:&lt;/i> director
&lt;i>Age:&lt;/i> 31
&lt;i>Height:&lt;/i> 1.59 m
Director, manager, and cameraman. Tries to turn his passion project into profitable business, with limited success. Likes beards, team-building exercises, and the sense of camaraderie. Didn’t make the list of suspects due to being the only one who didn’t know the victim’s account credentials.
</Profile>
	</ProfileList>
	<BlogList>
		<Blog>Dear friends,

Let me start with saying how grateful I am to be part of this wonderful community. It’s always been my dream to put a smile on people’s faces, but little did I know how real this dream would become. No, two years ago, on that faithful day when my friend Boyd suggested we do a show together, I thought nothing of the sort… I didn’t even dare to. But I said “yes” anyway, and started an unforgettable journey. All this time you have supported me with unconditional love, and I tried to give back the best I could. It’s been an amazing ride. A life-changing ride, really. But all rides come to an end sooner or later, and I think it’s time to end mine.

I realize this message might come as a big surprise to you. You might ask why I have suddenly decided to quit something I’ve been enjoying so much – something that YOU have been enjoying so much. It’s hard to put into words, but the feeling’s been there for quite some time, and you know I’m the one who always trusts my intuition, even if I can’t rationally explain it.

As for the implications, let me assure that all necessary arrangements have been made, and my leave won’t compromise any quality or integrity of the content, even though it’s happening in the middle of the season. I’ve warned my teammates about this decision well in advance, and they’ve been working hard to alter the production accordingly. The inspiring stories will continue to be told. It will just happen without me.

Thank you once again for your support, and don’t look back.

Love,
Ashley
</Blog>
		<Blog>Hello everyone,
		
We’d like to make an important announcement regarding the most recent entry to our news column. That entry was NOT written by Ashley. Somebody hacked into her account and posted it under her name. Ashley has no plans to leave the show, and she never had.

Yes, it sounds just as weird to us as it does to you, but it’s true. Everything that was written in that post is a lie. Ashley is not quitting, no “arrangements” of any kind have been made, and we’re definitely not altering the production.

Once again: Ashley has NO plans to leave the show, and she never had.

We have no idea why would anyone do such a thing, and we are regretfully in no position to track the offender down. However, we managed to restore Ashley’s account and took steps at ensuring its safety. No other harm was done, and we continue to work on the future episodes, right on schedule.

We apologize to everyone who was confused or upset by this incident. None of this is Ashley’s fault, but as a team we’d like to acknowledge our responsibility for not taking security matters more seriously. This will not happen again.

We also ask you to be empathic toward our Ashley. Whoever did this, they most likely planned it as a psychological attack on her, so now would a perfect time to show her your support. As for our side, we have zero doubts that the whole nasty occurrence will soon be a thing of the past. This community is amazing, and it will take much more than this to throw us into disarray.

All the best,
Boyd and the rest of the team
</Blog>
		<Blog>For the first time in a while, I have no idea what to write here. Words just aren’t coming. I think I used to have the same problem a couple of years ago. Before the show started… before I found my voice.

I spent the day reading through my previous posts. Funny, when I first decided to start a proper blog, I thought it needs to be very contemplative. Like old paper diaries where young girls wrote about love, and feelings, and meaning of life, and other deep things they could discuss with no one but themselves. But when I look at the past six months of content, all I see is routine. Anne and I went shopping, fooling around with clothes. Cloe and Zoe came by, had a jam session together. Here’s a funny book I read, you guys should try it too. Pulled an all-nighter with Boyd. Here’s a photoshoot with Viv; she’s my hero. Hey, we’ve released a new episode, thank you guys so much for your support, yay! Meetings, hangouts, plans, projects… what a busy girl.

You know, that thing about finding my voice – that wasn’t even a metaphor. Not some cheesy little extra you add just to make it sound more heartwarming and emotional. There wasn’t a slightest doubt in my mind. I thoroughly convinced myself that this is it – this is my place in the universe. Some people dance. Some are artists. Some swim. I entertain. I make someone’s evening a little bit brighter, give them more energy to face another day. And in the middle of all that – you. The viewers. The collective consciousness that links everything together and makes it meaningful.

It’s just… so hard to experience delayed failure. Normal failure is just fine by comparison. But when “sorry, it didn’t work out” part is preceded by months and months of allegedly successful work… it’s too confusing. You keep investing, you settle down in your new wonderful life… but then it all comes crashing down. And the joy, the feelings of happiness  – they are gone as well, because it’s all been interconnected in your brain. I prided myself on entertaining people with fiction, yet I completely fell apart when my own reality turned out to be fiction as well. How ironic.

Or maybe the path of destiny continues. Some places in the universe are just less grand than others. Who I am to deny mine just because it’s got less fun? The people have spoken: they told me to quit. Only I don’t know how to quit this and then start something else. Don’t have the slightest idea. Quitting everything altogether, on the other hand… that is something conceivable. Logical, even. Perhaps this is exactly what I should do.
</Blog>
	</BlogList>
	<Discussion>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Carol Dunn (July 13, 20:19)&lt;/color> Phew, that was a close one. I thought my favorite show was dead. Cheers for how you’ve handled this, guys, even if it was a bit slow.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Jim Christinsen (July 13, 20:24)&lt;/color> Don’t worry Ash we love you!

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Sung Xiu (July 13, 20:32)&lt;/color> Ashley support thread, coming right up.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Abigail Romero (July 13, 22:07)&lt;/color> I sure hope she’s alright. It’s always such an inspiration to see her on screen.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ngo Thu Huyen (July 14, 0:05)&lt;/color> Personally, I’d follow her anywhere, and support any choice she makes. But if she stays, it’s even better. She and the others have a really good chemistry in the series.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Bellona Lechner (July 14, 19:01)&lt;/color> Haters gonna hate. I’d say let them go and let the real fans stay. This community will be even better after a little clean-up.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Tsuya Matsumoto (July 14, 21:19)&lt;/color> Ashley, you are brilliant, and the fact that you are staying fills us with nothing but happiness. Keep spreading the love!

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Walter Clark (July 13, 20:40)&lt;/color> Why would anyone fake such a thing? Sounds like you guys just can’t admit your actress messed this up.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Grigory Borisov (July 13, 20:45)&lt;/color> Nope too late we don’t need you anymore

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Jamie Logan (July 13, 20:55)&lt;/color> LOL that was a cheap way to get more attention you whore
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Jim Christinsen (July 13, 21:17)&lt;/color> The only attention whore here is you jerkass
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Grigory Borisov (July 14, 1:30)&lt;/color> See, that’s the kind of internet I miss these days.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gary Jackson (July 13, 22:45)&lt;/color> A hacked account? What is she, an undercover operative?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Carol Dunn (July 13, 23:30)&lt;/color> Why does she have to be an undercover operative?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gary Jackson (July 13, 23:40)&lt;/color> Well, she doesn’t, but she needs to be someone important. Do you realize how hard it is to do the hacking these days? No way somebody would spend such resources on an actress from a relatively small web show.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Carol Dunn (July 14, 2:02)&lt;/color> Maybe somebody just had a lot of spare time on their hands.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gary Jackson (July 14, 9:05)&lt;/color> Yeah, and a brain of an absolute genius. The internet security has matured. It can’t be compromised by bored kids anymore.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gong Huangfu (July 13, 23:12)&lt;/color> I… I don’t know how to feel about it. I like Ashley, but this explanation makes no sense, sorry guys. Hacking? Psychological attack? I thought you’re supposed to create drama in the show, not around it.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Nishi Mishra (July 14, 1:20)&lt;/color> All right, I was keeping it to myself because I didn’t want to start the flame war, but now the cat is out of the bag anyway, so here goes: Ashley, please consider taking a break. You’re amazing, but you’ve been driving yourself too hard, and it shows, both on and off screen.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Kao Wei (July 14, 11:05)&lt;/color> Are you just trying to stir things up on purpose? Because it won’t work, you know. We’ve tolerated your cutesy lead and her rabid fanbase for a long time, but something has to be done sooner or later. And considering her total lack of skills, quitting is the only real option.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Barbara Brooks (July 14, 23:10)&lt;/color> I concur. I’d recommend sending Ashley to an actual drama school, but I know for a fact that won’t work either.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Kim Phan (July 14, 13:14)&lt;/color> Why does it always have to be about your precious Ashley? Why not consider how we feel? It was a psychological attack on us fans as well. We invest in your show.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gong Huangfu (July 14, 18:01)&lt;/color> THIS. Her resignation post hit me so hard, I was actually shaking. I can’t believe I had such a reaction over a stupid web series. I’m getting too emotional for this shit.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Stephanie Taylor (July 14, 15:59)&lt;/color> Now, why do we have to be so dramatic about this, folks? Even if it’s been going downhill, there’s nothing a good long break can’t fix. Why should she quit forever?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Sung Xiu (July 14, 19:12)&lt;/color> They’ll lose most of the audience. There are so many alternatives, people will just forget about it move on to some other show. It’s a very competitive environment.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Kao Wei (July 14, 20:10)&lt;/color> No break can fix such shitty acting.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Yewande Awe (July 14, 18:32)&lt;/color> If you don’t like it, don’t watch it. No need to force other people to quit doing what they love. They owe you nothing.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Kim Phan (July 14, 19:04)&lt;/color> Actually, they do. We support the series with our time and money. We deserve to have a saying in what direction it should go.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Yewande Awe (July 14, 19:09)&lt;/color> Money? I didn’t know this show was crowd-funded.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Stephanie Taylor (July 14, 19:15)&lt;/color> I think he’s talking about merch and subs-only features.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Grigory Borisov (July 14, 20:00)&lt;/color> Don’t even mention subs-only features… putting content behind the paywall has damaged their support more than bland acting could ever do.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Stephanie Taylor (July 14. 20:19)&lt;/color> It’s only behind-the-scenes commentary and other little extras that are subscription-only. Not unreasonable to try and get profit from something, is it?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Bellona Lechner (July 14, 21:36)&lt;/color> Anyone who calls Ashley’s acting “bland” need to get their eyes replaced. And ears. And brain.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Barbara Brooks (July 14, 23:20)&lt;/color> It IS bland. You should try to watch some serious movies for a change. Being cute is not enough to be a good actress.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Leonidas Paterakis (July 14, 21:05)&lt;/color> Can someone explain why is everybody making such a fuss over it? Actors get changed all the time. Whether she’s out or not, they can always find another one. As long as nobody with the vision (director, writers) leaves, the show will be fine.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Jim Christinsen (July 14, 21:09)&lt;/color> You stupid idiot Ashley is the reason this show is still alive
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Leonidas Paterakis (July 14, 21:25)&lt;/color> I was asking for an explanation, not fanboyish hysteria.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Bellona Lechner (July 14, 21:44)&lt;/color> Don’t ask stupid questions if you don’t want to get stupid answers. The fact that Ashley is the main driving force is clear to anyone who’s bothered to look.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Leonidas Paterakis (July 14, 22:05)&lt;/color> Looks like fanboys is the only kind of fans she has. Oh, well.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Barbara Brooks (July 14, 23:00)&lt;/color> Oh, great, another prima donna is going to entertain herself with a string of final goodbyes and unexpected comebacks. I used to enjoy her acting, but the last months have been a disaster. Just do this community a favor and step down gracefully.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Walter Clark (July 14, 23:40)&lt;/color> This person gets it. That’s exactly the kind of nonsense that splits good teams apart. They’re making a big mistake covering for her instead of just kicking her out.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Abigail Romero (July 15, 9:06)&lt;/color> I can’t believe so many people are actually driving Ashley away. I thought she was fan’s favorite. WTF is wrong with the world today?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gary Jackson (July 15, 12:10)&lt;/color> There’s nothing inherently strange with this sudden reaction. They simply got an incentive to say what’s been on their minds for a long time. The society told us to be polite and get along with each other, so we keep uncomfortable things to ourselves until we just can’t hide it anymore.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Abigail Romero (July 15, 15:53)&lt;/color> Well, when you put it that way… still, it’s hard to believe.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Gary Jackson (July 15, 17:35)&lt;/color> I personally don’t like it either. I’d much rather we are honest and direct. But that’s the world we live in: people avoid conflicts. Even when it’s as simple as telling your favorite actress she lost her spark.

&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Deborah Sullivan (July 15, 17:00)&lt;/color> It pains me to say this, but I agree that Ashley will be better off trying something new. The new season is ok, but it just doesn’t have the same spark. I believe that she didn’t write that post (what’s the point in lying?), but maybe it was a sign.</Discussion>
	<ErrorMessage>&lt;color=#FF0000>Error: invalid link&lt;/color></ErrorMessage>
	<CommenterList>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Abigail Romero&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> May 12, 2023 (age 25)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Belo Horizonte, Brazil
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Belo Horizonte, Brazil
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 2018 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>12:38 21.07 – world.news: story of the day, discussion thread
12:30 21.07 – world.news: local entertainment, article #53, discussion thread
12:15 21.07 – world.news: personalized reading recommendation
12:05 21.07 – check.your.chances: traffic inquiry
12:02 21.07 – check.your.chances: general inquiry
11:50 21.07 – c.store.america: furniture section, shopping bill
11:39 21.07 – c.store.america: scheduled groceries delivery
11:20 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #1267, review section
11:07 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #1258, comment section
10:52 21.07 – life.plus: medical department section, daily health check
10:51 21.07 – r.d.r.support: automated robot maintenance
10:34 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 2098674, log id A7YTR5
10:17 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 8764534, log id 8IU5IU
10:10 21.07 – smart.eating: recommended meal inquiry
09:56 21.07 – move.live: cardio workout, 190 calories
[2003 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Barbara Brooks&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> April 10, 2012 (age 36)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Sydney, Australia
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Sydney, Australia
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1055 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Bellona Lechner&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> September 2, 2030 (age 17)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Sheffield, England
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Edinburgh, Scotland
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 2432 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>14:00 21.07 – museums.of.scotland: Edinburgh Castle, guided tour
13:31 21.07 – museums.of.scotland: Edinburgh Castle, ticket purchase
13:12 21.07 – the.royal.mile: restaurant bill
12:50 21.07 – smart.eating: recommended meal inquiry
12:43 21.07 – europe.retail: clothing section, shopping bill
11:50 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 7811206, log id NB22X5
11:47 21.07 – rail.uk: public transportation, 320 km
09:41 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 7811206, log id ZAPO78
09:38 21.07 – rail.uk: train Sheffield – Edinburgh, ticket purchase
09:30 21.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 8.3 km
09:01 21.07 – smart.eating: recommended meal inquiry
00:57 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #18977, comment section
00:52 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #15406, comment section
00:44 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #12101, comment section
00:41 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #8100, comment section
[2417 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Carol Dunn&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> December 11, 2021 (age 26)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Santa Fe, Argentina
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Santa Fe, Argentina
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1578 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>12:59 21.07 – video.time: education programs, content #126, rating
11:56 21.07 – c.store.america: kitchenware section, shopping bill
11:42 21.07 – take.care: client personalized recommendations access
11:01 21.07 – take.care: client id 5541222, caregiver id 408M, session start
10:49 21.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 26.5 km
10:20 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 5541222, log id PW875N
10:14 21.07 – video.time: short films, content #31098, rating
10:01 21.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #1258, comment section
10:00 21.07 – video.time: extra features access, monthly subscription fee
09:50 21.07 – tasteful.museums.group: temporary exhibitions, ticket purchase
09:18 21.07 – smart.eating: recommended meal inquiry
09:15 21.07 – c.store.america: scheduled groceries delivery
08:58 21.07 – move.live: strength training, 80 calories
08:25 21.07 – move.live: running, 4.45 km
07:57 21.07 – move.live: personalized fitness recommendation
[1563 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Deborah Sullivan&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> March 25, 2026 (age 22)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Salt Lake City, United States
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Salt Lake City, United States
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1890 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Gary Jackson&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> July 5, 2018 (age 30)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Austin, United States
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Austin, United States
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1270 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Gong Huangfu&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> January 15, 2009 (age 39)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Shenzhen, China
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Hong Kong, China
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1950 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>14:03 21.07 – clear.connect: conference call, 5 participants, log id U88R3X
13:42 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, caller id 3467100, log id VC23Q6
13:15 21.07 – life.plus.hq: internal tools, code generator
12:51 21.07 – life.plus.hq: internal tools, algorithm builder
12:32 21.07 – life.plus.hq: simulation platform, resources request
12:10 21.07 – life.plus.hq: core database access, query id 1476
11:59 21.07 – life.plus.hq: development roadmaps, project #14B, modification
11:46 21.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id KL8711, modification
11:38 21.07 – edu.future: statistics section, parental inquiry
11:34 21.07 – music.time: country pop, personalized playlist generation
11:09 21.07 – clear.connect: conference call, 7 participants, log id J4H4B2
10:52 21.07 – life.plus.hq: software division, employee id 176T, entrance
10:48 21.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 31 km
10:06 21.07 – check.your.chances: general inquiry
10:00 21.07 – music.time: independent artists, monthly support donation
[1935 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Grigory Borisov&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> April 20, 2012 (age 36)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Minsk, Belarus
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Delhi, India
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1710 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Jamie Logan&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> August 10, 2028 (age 19)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Lagos, Nigeria
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Lagos, Nigeria
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1120 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Jim Christinsen&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> April 28, 2033 (age 15)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Cairo, Egypt
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Cairo, Egypt
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1223 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>13:34 21.07 – edu.future: VR class, biology, 8 participants
12:48 21.07 – edu.future: VR class, physics, 14 participants
11:12 21.07 – edu.future: personalized math lesson, complexity level 2C
10:54 21.07 – edu.future: automated roadmap adjustment
10:50 21.07 – music.time: power metal, friends’ playlists request
23:20 20.07 – gaming.time: military shooters, Quantum Warfare
22:17 20.07 – gaming.time: VR action-adventures, Space Pirate’s Creed
21:15 20.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #16502, comment section
21:12 20.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #12455, comment section
21:08 20.07 – video.time: movies, content #572, review
15:12 20.07 – video.time: binge-watching personalized recommendation
13:11 20.07 – clear.connect: chat room, 12 participants, log id 17U8AX
12:34 20.07 – edu.future: math test, 63% performance
12:08 20.07 – edu.future: English test, 89% performance
11:35 20.07 – check.your.chances: exam preparedness inquiry
[1208 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Kao Wei&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> October 4, 2029 (age 28)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Shanghai, China
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Shanghai, China
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1450 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Kim Phan&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> August 31, 2030 (age 17)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Ho Chi Min City, Vietnam
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Guangzhou, China
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1396 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>06:52 21.07 – hotel.classic: check-in, 1 night, double room
06:37 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: dance club venue #87, bar tab payment
05:25 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: dance club venue #87, dance floor music request
04:14 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: dance club venue #87, entrance fee
04:01 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: karaoke bar #145, tab payment
02:52 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: karaoke bar #145, k-pop, random playlist request
01:58 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: Irish pub #31, drinking challenge 2nd prize
01:30 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: Irish pub #31, drinking challenge contender fee
00:42 21.07 – chinese.nightlife: Irish pub #31, buffet bill
23:28 20.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 18.4 km
22:46 20.07 – clear.connect: video call, caller id 1887575, log id 43FV3B
22:40 20.07 – second.half: online dating service, user id 1887575, invitation
22:32 20.07 – second.half: online dating service, matchmaking request
22:17 20.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 4512988, log id DS0S05
22:10 20.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 4521011, log id BK111E 
[1381 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Leonidas Paterakis&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> July 11, 2004 (age 44)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> London, England
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> London, England
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1670 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Ngo Thu Huyen&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> November 1, 2022 (age 25)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Hanoi, Vietnam
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Hanoi, Vietnam
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1875 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>13:42 21.07 – edu.future: navigator services, chemical engineering, student id 567KJ
12:50 21.07 – edu.future: navigator services, organic chemistry, student id 891LP
12:25 21.07 – edu.future: navigator services, basic chemistry, student id 126AA
11:20 21.07 – c.store.asia: scheduled groceries delivery
11:00 21.07 – life.plus: medical department section, automated prescription renewal
10:52 21.07 – life.plus: medical department section, daily health check
22:10 20.07 – asian.food.group: restaurant bill
21:03 20.07 – smart.eating: recommended meal inquiry
19:32 20.07 – puppet.theater: evening special, tickets purchase
19:25 20.07 – clear.connect: video call, caller id 3098777, log id JL231L
19:20 20.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 10.2 km
19:04 20.07 – check.your.chances: safety inquiry
19:01 20.07 – check.your.chances: traffic inquiry
18:20 20.07 – move.live: yoga class, 5 participants
18:10 20.07 – music.time: folk, new releases playlist request
[1860 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Nishi Mishra&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> February 24, 2027 (age 21)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Mumbai, India
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Mumbai, India
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1493 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>13:06 21.07 – life.plus.hq: energy division, laboratory 5 access
12:52 21.07 – life.plus.hq: development roadmaps, project #22K, addition
12:38 21.07 – life.plus.hq: development roadmaps, project #21K, modification
12:10 21.07 – life.plus.hq: simulation platform, scheduled session
11:42 21.07 – life.plus.hq: infrastructure, cafeteria order
11:31 21.07 – life.plus.hq: energy division, employee id 441Q, entrance
02:05 21.07 – music.time: blues, “best of” playlist request
01:58 21.07 – take.care: Caregivers Asian Association, donation
01:51 21.07 – charity.united: Disaster Relief Fund, donation
01:32 21.07 – video.time: education programs, content #451, rating
00:42 21.07 – video.time: education programs, content #378, rating
00:12 21.07 – world.news: story of the day, discussion thread
23:59 20.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #18977, comment section
22:12 20.07 – life.plus.hq: energy division, employee id 441Q, exit
21:07 20.07 – life.plus.hq: infrastructure, cafeteria order
[1478 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Stephanie Taylor&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> January 4, 2018 (age 30)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Manila, Philippines
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Karachi, Pakistan
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 989 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>12:01 20.07 – just.as.planned: personal reminders, new event
11:30 21.07 – charity.united: SWAC, conference panel #12, moderator
01:21 21.07 – clear.connect: chat room, 4 participants, log id J7K6Y1
23:34 20.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #17223, comment section
23:12 20.07 – video.time: short films, content #11755, rating
22:09 20.07 – hotel.classic: room service request
21:18 20.07 – world.news: social issues, article submission
20:57 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 975LL, modification
15:30 20.07 – charity.united: SWAC, conference talk #34, speaker
14:49 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 1276IJ, sharing
14:31 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 1276IJ, modification
11:21 20.07 – clear.connect: conference call, 6 participants, log id REQ661
10:07 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 1276IJ, modification
09:12 20.07 – charity.united: SWAC, attendee id 94N, registration
09:00 20.07 – charity.united: event reminder, Social Workers Annual Conference
[974 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Sung Xiu&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> November 21, 2024 (age 23)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Hong Kong, China
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Lima, Peru
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 2201 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>10:31 21.07 – augment.it: entertainment mode, thrill-seeking session start
10:23 21.07 – peru.experience: amusement park, ticket purchase
22:08 20.07 – fusion.cuisine: restaurant bill
20:51 20.07 – peru.experience: water fountains show, park entrance ticket purchase
17:01 20.07 – peru.experience: Peruvian cooking class
15:38 20.07 – peru.experience: national cuisine food tour
13:16 20.07 – peru.experience: historic center walking tour
12:57 20.07 – augment.it: tourist mode, cultural discoveries session start
12:43 20.07 – augment.it: tourist mode, area overview request
12:38 20.07 – check.your.chances: timeframes inquiry
12:32 20.07 – check.your.chances: safety inquiry
12:12 20.07 – hotel.classic: check-in, 3 nights, family room
12:05 20.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 17 km
11:40 20.07 – global.airlines: flight 6789OP, Mexico City – Lima, baggage claim
09:04 20.07 – global.airlines: flight 6789OP, Mexico City – Lima, check-in
[2186 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Tsuya Matsumoto&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> February 15, 2022 (age 26)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Tokyo, Japan
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Yokohama, Japan
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1808 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>12:29 21.07 – japan.retail: personal electronics section, shopping bill
12:09 21.07 – world.news: science &amp; technology, article #76, discussion thread
12:05 21.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 14.4 km
11:37 21.07 – asian.food.group: breakfast bill
11:34 21.07 – world.news: global culture, article #12, discussion thread
11:28 21.07 – world.news: science &amp; technology, article #76, discussion thread
11:12 21.07 – smart.eating: recommended meal inquiry
11:06 21.07 – travel.anywhere: public transportation, 7.2 km
10:44 21.07 – just.as.planned: personal reminders, new event
10:39 21.07 – just.as.planned: personal reminders, new task
10:30 21.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 1125062, log id QMM897
10:21 21.07 – hotel.classic: check-out, 1 night, single room
22:31 20.07 – hotel.classic: room service request
22:07 20.07 – move.live: running, 10.45 km
21:12 20.07 – reading.time: audio books, content id #542, bookmark loading
[1793 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Walter Clark&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> August 1, 2012 (age 35)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> New York, United States
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Singapore
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 2120 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History></History>
		</Commenter>
		<Commenter>
			<Profile>&lt;b>&lt;i>Name:&lt;/i> Yewande Awe&lt;/b>
&lt;i>Born:&lt;/i> September 30, 2027 (age 20)
&lt;i>Place of residence:&lt;/i> Johannesburg, South Africa
&lt;i>Latest log in from:&lt;/i> Johannesburg, South Africa
&lt;i>Recent activity:&lt;/i> 1405 entries in 4 weeks [view]</Profile>
			<History>01:41 21.07 – reading.time: science fiction, content id #122, review
00:56 21.07 – reading.time: comedy &amp; romance, content id #411, comment section
00:17 21.07 – reading.time: short stories, independent submission
22:18 20.07 – experimental.cuisine: restaurant bill
22:09 20.07 – clear.connect: video call, caller id 7521925, log id NM4B4K
20:37 20.07 – r.d.r.support: manual robot maintenance, client id 1205919
20:11 20.07 – r.d.r.support: manual robot maintenance, client id 7630031
19:20 20.07 – r.d.r.support: manual robot maintenance, client id 4088045
18:42 20.07 – music.time: classical crossover, personalized playlist generation
17:50 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 75XW1Z, sharing
17:36 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 75XW1Z, automated editor request
17:11 20.07 – life.plus.cloud: document id 75XW1Z, modification
16:32 20.07 – clear.connect: video call, recipient id 7521925, log id PL334C
16:30 20.07 – just.as.planned: personal reminders, scheduled event
16:01 20.07 – video.time: VR shows, content #5407, comment section
[1390 older entries are available]</History>
		</Commenter>
	</CommenterList>
	<MeetupList>
		<Meetup>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Don’t tell you’re here since 9 AM sharp. It’s not an office job, you know.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> That’s fine… I didn’t have anything else to do this morning.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> So… I’m to help you with the sensory stuff, right? Can you walk me through it?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Sure. You know how a typical virtual reality headset works?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Eh… not really, sorry. I’ve used VR many times, of course, but never actually bothered to figure out the mechanics.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> It’s all right, I’ll explain. Let me just get mine out of the bag…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> That’s a slick-looking red thingie. Did you choose it to match your hair?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> I did, actually. So… the first important part is that it covers your entire field of vision. That’s kinda the point; if you have bits of reality left on the periphery, you might as well take the thing off and watch your show on a flat screen, the old-fashioned way.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Ha, right.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Next, we have these extensions that cover your nose and cheeks. They regulate the temperature inside, blow streams of air to simulate the wind, and also contain scent cartridges that distribute tiny amounts of gas next to your nostrils. They have a limited amount of chemicals, of course, and you can always get spares, but these days it’s optimized so well that you won’t need a refill for a long time.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Looks simple so far.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> What’s also important is that cartridges don’t contain a smell for every possible occasion. There is a limited scent palette, and generally you’ll have to mix the basics in different proportions to get something specific and realistic. So, doing scents is akin to being a sound designer who makes an audio track for a movie from his collection of simple effects. Sometimes it’s straightforward; sometimes you need to get creative. I actually spent some time mixing our own library of scents, so you won’t have to worry much about chemistry. It doesn’t have everything, but it should give you an instant solution for the typical stuff… the kind of stuff you’d expect to encounter in a show like ours, anyway.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Cool, thanks. And touch? You need gloves for that, right?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Yes. Most of these apply pressure to your palms in different patterns to simulate various surface textures. Some can also regulate temperature to make it cool or warm, generate moist if you need something wet and even trigger mild pain. In our case it’s usually less varied than scents, so you should be fine with standard presets; just familiarize yourself with them.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> And… don’t mean to question your work here, but… is it worth it? Does it really make the show better?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Well… generally, it’s up to debate. Some will call it a useless gimmick and say that the plot is still the most important thing, with the rules of storytelling not changing since prehistoric people shared tales by the campfire. Others will call it the future and tell you to go for total immersion. Most will be somewhere in between. But as for our own audience? They love it almost unanimously. Not a single episode is released without somebody leaving a shining comment about how they liked this fancy smell or that funny touch. So, for now, I’d say it’s a no brainer.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> So, basically, once you finish editing an episode, I will need to go through it and determine which effects to use and where.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> That’s right. What helps me, personally, is to draw a parallel between a web show and a video game. In a VR video game, you have an avatar that walks around and interacts with stuff. In a show, you’re a passive observer, but because it’s VR, you’re still part of the world. So you’re kinda still have an avatar, you just can’t move it; it goes wherever the camera goes, the path predetermined. But as long as the stuff is nearby, you can still interact with it. You can reach out your hand and feel a surface, or you can sniff your nose, which would trigger a response from the helmet to intensify the current scent. Ideally, all of this should be accounted for.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Okay…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Now, the good news is that you don’t need to worry about all senses all the time – the human brain won’t appreciate it anyway; it gives the most power to the senses you’re concentrating on, and moves everything else to the background. So, for any given scene in the show, think what should be naturally engaged. Like, if a character appears for the first time in fancy new clothes, sight is obviously important, and maybe a nice smell of perfume she’s wearing, but not the temperature around, because you wouldn’t care about it in real life, even if it’s really hot or cold; you would be momentarily distracted by her arrival. On the contrary, when two characters are having an idle conversation for quite some time, and you are outside, and it’s getting dark, then adding a touch of cold breeze might just be the right thing. You’re still with me?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Yeah, sure… I think I get it.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Wanna start with doing a few effects together? It should be a couple of hours until others arrive.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Of course, let’s do it.
(end of pre-selected fragment)</Meetup>
		<Meetup>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> All right, a couple of quick things. Sorry I’m not present in person, but this guy wants to meet today, and it looks worthwhile. Might be a great source of funding.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> As long as our artistic freedom is not sacrificed.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Nah, the dude gets it. You’ve got to nurture your talent. Like I nurture you guys.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Yeah, yeah, best boss ever. When do we film?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> As soon as we finish with the existing footage. I’ll need a very clear picture of where we are now, and the only way to provide that is to get the end result. Should be enough there for three, maybe three and a half episodes. Ashley has agreed to edit it all.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Burning a tanker full of midnight oil again, girl? I’ll help, Boyd.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Thanks, Anne, much appreciated. We need our Ash fresh and healthy for the shooting of our season finale.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> And the script?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Cloe is putting in the final touches. I think you people will love it.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> I think I’d love my own script even more…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Karl, you know I can’t give you anything mid-season, when the deadlines are starting to get real.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> What can I say? You can’t rush a masterpiece.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Yeah, I’m not even trying at this point… but I read Cloe’s near-finished version, and I honestly think she did a great job. I have a lot of awesomeness visualized in my head right now, and if it comes to life, this will end up being our best season yet. We might even have trouble topping it further down the road.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> Wrong! Our journey will continue upwards, as far as it takes!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Oh hey, Vivienne, haven’t noticed you there. Who are you this time?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> I’m the mighty Kamina! The man of indomitable spirit and masculinity! You’d better remember that.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> That didn’t really help. It’s always some kind of ancient cult classic, right?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Be thankful you’ve missed the last time. It was a radio host of some sort. Wouldn’t shut up about “hooded figures” and “the dog park.”
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Knowing her, she’s probably nailed it again. Got all the little things right, and we can’t even appreciate them.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> I hear ya. The subtle references are wasted on us. Anyhow, I’m thinking about two days of shooting. 8-hours straight, just the way you like it. Outdoor scenes when the weather is right, indoor scenes otherwise. The indoor set is prepped and all yours, Anne.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Sure thing. Shall I start whenever?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Yeah, do your props and lighting magic; Cloe should fill you in on what we’re aiming for. Just don’t go overboard, and please don’t turn this into a weightlifting championship again; we need you fresh and healthy as well, even if you’re not on screen. If something heavy needs to be moved, call me, I’m good at dumb manual labor.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Got it. Thanks, Boyd.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> We’ll also need a costume for Karl and the makeup done for all three of you… which I assume won’t be a problem for our Vivienne.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> Just who the hell do you think I am?!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Right, I’ll take that as “yes.” And if anyone has friends who want to play extra, now is the time to invite them for our park scene. We’ll need 15, maybe 20 people. 25 if we do some sweeping shots, but that’s the limit.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> Simon! How many times did I tell you? You are a spiral being! Spiral beings have no limits!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Who’s Simon?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Is there any point in asking?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Oh, and while we’re having fun on set, Daniel is going to do effects integration. Ash, I hope you can patiently show him the ropes until then and resist doing everything quickly by yourself.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Don’t worry, I get it. Teach a man to fish and all that.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Some people are just incapable of fishing…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> Believe in me, Simon! Do not believe in him, believe in me! Believe in Kamina who believes in him!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Boyd:&lt;/color> Yeah, what she said. And… that about covers it. Now, excuse me, I have to go and court our supposedly juicy investor. Everyone, thanks for your time.
(end of pre-selected fragment)</Meetup>
		<Meetup>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Mm… mm-hmm… hey, that’s a nice one… oh, chamomile, I feel relaxed already… mm, that’s a nice strawberry… and a touch of vanilla… WHA… what on earth was that? Was that a fart?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Sorry? Oh, yeah, I did those. Four types.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Four farts?!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Yep. Depending on the food one might’ve eaten before.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> You’re messing with me.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Just imagine the possibilities! You can’t deny that VR took fart jokes to a whole new level.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> What a time to be alive.
(laughter)
(Daniel takes the headset off)
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> But honestly, this library is amazing. You must have spent months making it.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> It was fun.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> How do you manage to do this?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Do what?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Pour so much heart and soul into this thing?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> He, well… we’re all given a lot of days in this life. Might as well spend them on something.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> But don’t you ever want something more… tangible? Like, a real job?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> And what’s a “real job”?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Something that pays well, for starters.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> You know we do get some money out of this.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Not enough to pay the bills. Come on, you know what I mean. Working for some nice big company, getting a juicy paycheck every month, never having to worry that the whole thing might fall apart tomorrow… sounds nice, right?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> For somebody else, perhaps. I’m not cut out for the corporate world. I’d rather be a part-time waitress than give up doing what I love.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> That’s weird… and amazing. Weird and amazing at the same time.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> He-he… I’ll take that as a compliment.
(silence)
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Hey, Ashley, I’ve been meaning to ask you… do you wanna go out with me?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> What’s that, sorry?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Go out with me. I really like you.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Eh… okay, this is really awkward… I appreciate you’re asking me, Dan… but I’m not really interested.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Are you sure?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> I’m sure. You’re a really nice guy, and I’m sorry if I gave you the wrong impression, but… yeah. Sorry.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> If you need some time to think about it, that’s fine.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Time is not the issue here… I’m just not interested.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> I mean, there’s no need to rush or anything. Just one date. I know this great place…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> No, seriously. I value you as a friend, but I don’t want to take it any further.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Come on, Ash, just give me a chance. I promise I’ll make it worth your while.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Dan, please. I made up my mind.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> But if you could only turn away from your screens and listen to me for a moment…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> I did that, Dan. I started to listen very carefully when I realized how serious your request is. And I said no. No means no. Please don’t turn this into a problem.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> I just…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Stop. Just stop, okay?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Ugh… unbelievable. I guess I’ll get out of here then.
(end of pre-selected fragment)</Meetup>
		<Meetup>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Hey, Ash. Editing?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Oh, hey, Anne. Yes…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Leave an episode or two for me. I promised to help.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> What? Oh, right… just a moment…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Did something happen? You look much more preoccupied than you were before.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> I… Dan asked me out.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> What? Like, while you were helping him with the effects?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Yes. I said no.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Oh… I assume he didn’t take it very well.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> That’s the problem; he didn’t take it at all. He just kept going, so I had to put my foot down, and it got really awkward, and…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> I’m sorry you had to go through that, darling.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> You think I did the wrong thing?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> What? Of course not! You’re not remotely interested in the guy, right?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Yeah.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Than how can you even ask that?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> But I hurt him. At least I think I did… he sure left the room pretty fast.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> That should be irrelevant, isn’t it? When somebody asks you out, you respond, and they live with it, as simple as that. If he can’t take “no” for an answer, that’s entirely his problem.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Yes, but…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Look, Ash, I know how considerate you are. Hell, you’re the most caring person I’ve met, and I love you so much for that. But some people don’t deserve your empathy. I’ve always thought that guy is no good… you shouldn’t worry about him so much.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> That’s just not who I am, Anne… I care for people. Even if I get burned, I keep looking for the good side. All the work I’m doing here – there is no point in it if I don’t.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> I know, sweetie. But you can’t sacrifice yourself.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> It’s always hard to tell when I stop investing and start sacrificing…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> And that’s why I’m here. You care for everybody, I care for you. Come on, chin up. Let’s go get some fresh air and a nice cup of ice coffee. The weather is awesome today.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Thanks, Anne… just give me a moment, all right?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Anne:&lt;/color> Sure thing.
(end of pre-selected fragment)</Meetup>
		<Meetup>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> …so what I’m saying is that, under certain circumstances – not always, but when it’s most susceptible, like being exhausted, for example – you can really fool a human’s brain. If images and sounds and smells are realistic and relentless enough, your mind stops discerning between virtual and real. You just “fall” into whatever’s happening inside your headset, and it becomes your new real life.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Where did you even get that?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> A number of independent places, actually. Just don’t go questioning and scrutinizing my sources, it’s boring. Think about the idea itself.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> If that’s the case, shouldn’t it be happening all the time? VR is a mundane thing now, a harmless gimmick. People incorporate smells and touches into videos and games all the time, regardless of whether they actually need it or not. We’re doing it as well.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> It’s a matter of detail. They’re using it sparingly – a rosy fragrant here, a rough surface there, a stench of sewers if they’re bold. Nobody has tried to simulate it all, to replicate every little sensory element of reality. Maybe they’re afraid of uncanny valley. Or maybe they’re hiding behind this notion that brain concentrates on one-two senses at a time. But that’s just wrong; you might as well say “sight gives us 80% of information, so let’s not bother with anything else.” No, the little things matter. And if you really push the envelope, if you bombard it from all angles with endless high-quality data – that’s when things get weird.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Right…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> And the best part? To mess with the brain, you don’t even have to get inside it. Forget about neural interfaces and implants and other sci-fi shit – the tools are right here. You’re sitting in a chair with a bulky gizmo on your head – by all accounts, you should be aware it’s fake at all times, no matter what that gizmo is showing you. But you’re not.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Why does it feel like you’re selling me neuro-linguistic programming or similar nonsense?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> Please. I’m not talking about some magical programming instructions. The input is completely unexceptional – simply a hyper-realistic simulation. It’s just that our minds are fooled even more easily that we have thought.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> And why does that make you so excited again?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> Oh, you boring human being. Don’t you see the implications? Since the beginning, it’s been about increasing input channels; bridging the gap between us and made-up worlds more and more, one sense at a time. Text, still images, moving images, moving images with sound… but now we’re erasing the gap altogether. This is where the next revolution will come from. The last barrier between virtual and real will fall. And it’s. Gonna. Be. Glorious.
(Door opens; Ashley and Anne walk in)
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Hey, Cloe. Karl.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Hello, ladies. Cloe’s just been explaining to me why we need to make our show even more smelly.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> Get out of here.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Karl:&lt;/color> Yep, I think I’ll do just that. Charming to hang out with you, folks, but my work awaits me. Good luck with your revolution, penguin.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> My dear human… I myself broke that barrier a long time ago.
(End of pre-selected fragment)</Meetup>
		<Meetup>&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> And the whole thing’s happening at the park, so there are people around, and they can’t help but look at them, because she’s wearing these ragtag clothes, and he’s shaking badly, but then she just – bam! – and kisses him.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> A mad display of courage!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> And she says, “I am scared, but that’s all the more reason to do it. I want to be together, no matter what.”
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> A drill that pierces the heavens!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> But then her friend comes, and she has feelings for her as well, but she puts on her best smile and tries to be happy for them with all her might. So you kinda think that, while their struggles may be tough, she literally chose to face the impossible…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> …and kick the reason to the curb!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> Exactly! And you watch this woman, who was the fragile one all the time, act so strongly, and you think about how fragility and strength are closely intertwined in humans and this kind of stuff…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> At times like this, I remember looking at Simon’s back as he dug tirelessly. I wanted to become a man whose back would never break.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> But then a crack in her facade appears, and it’s not clear whether the other two notice it, but it’s definitely might become a problem no matter how hard she tries, so you get all emotional and impatiently wait for the next season. Anyway, shall we call it a day?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> It’s been a glorious day, comrades. Let us rest so we can continue to drill the path to our future tomorrow!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> Ash, you coming?
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Yeah, just a moment…
(Door opens; Daniel quickly walks in)
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Thank God you’re still here! Ashley, I’m so sorry. I’ve been replaying our conversation in my head over and over again until I realized how disgusting I was.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Daniel…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> You said “no,” and I respect that. I should have respected that… please forgive me.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> … it’s okay.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> I’m such an idiot… now I’m going to lose your friendship as well, and I don’t want to lose that… I know I deserve it, but I don’t want to…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> Dan… it’s okay. Don’t worry.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Thank you…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> I can’t offer you a relationship, but I don’t intend to throw you away either. If you’re all right with just a person who cares about you as a human being, then I’m right here.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Daniel:&lt;/color> Thank you. You’re amazing. Thank you so much…
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> Simon! Good job. Be sure to return that love tenfold!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> He didn’t get the girl, you silly.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Vivienne:&lt;/color> Neither did I!
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Ashley:&lt;/color> I… I’m not sure which one of us was supposed to be Simon this time.
&lt;color=#BCE9FF>Cloe:&lt;/color> Don’t you get it? Simon is everyone. And everyone is Simon. Come on, humans, let’s go home.
(End of pre-selected fragment)</Meetup>
	</MeetupList>
</Root>